片名：奇幻人生
故事的主角是一个叫哈罗德·克里克的男人
This is a story about a man named Harold Crick.
还有他的手表
And his wristwatch.
哈罗德生活中充满了数不清的数字 算术
Harold Crick was a man of infinite numbers...
自己却少言寡语
...endless calculations and remarkably few words.
他的手表话就更少了
And his wristwatch said even less.
12年来 每个工作日
Every weekday, for 1 2 years...
哈罗德都要刷上他32颗牙齿 每颗76遍
...Harold would brush each of his 32 teeth 7 6 times.
来回38遍
Thirty-eight times back and forth.
上下38遍
Thirty-eight times up and down.
12年来 每个工作日
Every weekday, for 1 2 years...
哈罗德都会在领带上打单温莎结 而不是双结…
...Harold would tie his tie in a single Windsor knot instead of the double...
因此能省去43秒时间
...thereby saving up to 43 seconds.
他的手表觉得单温莎结让他的脖子 看上去更肥…
His wristwatch thought the single Windsor made his neck look fat...
…但是什么也不说
...but said nothing.
12年来 每个工作日
Every weekday, for 1 2 years...
哈罗德几乎都以每街区57步的速率 走过6个街区
...Harold would run at a rate of nearly 57 steps per block for six blocks...
刚好赶上8点17分克罗内克的公车
...barely catching the 8: 1 7 Kronecker bus.
清风拂面…
His wristwatch would delight...
令他的手表感到舒服
...in the feeling of the crisp wind rushing over its face.
12年来 每个工作日
And every weekday, for 1 2 years...
作为国税局的高级审计员
...Harold would review 7. 1 34 tax files...
哈罗德都要审阅7.134份税务文件
...as a senior agent for the lnternal Revenue Service.
注册部1.469-2Bi 黛安 谢谢
Regs section 1 .469-2 (B) (i), Diane. Thanks.
早上好 美国国税局
Good morning. IRS.
哈罗德 89乘以1417是多少?
HaroId, 89 times 1 41 7?
126,113 1 26,1 1 3.
合计这么多
That adds up.
只用45.7分钟吃午餐
Only taking a 45. 7-minute lunch break...
4.3分钟喝咖啡
...and a 4.3-minute coffee break...
手表精确地记下这些时间
...timed precisely by his wristwatch.
哦 很好
Oh, great.
嗯 我们去穆兰那或者我们去…
Yeah, we'II go to MuIIen's or we'II....
除此之外 哈罗德生活很孤单
Beyond that, Harold lived a life of solitude.
独自步行回家
He would walk home alone.
独自吃饭
He would eat alone.
每晚11点13分
And at precisely 1 1: 1 3 every night...
哈罗德准时独自上床睡觉
...Harold would go to bed alone...
把他的手表放在身旁的床头几上
...placing his wristwatch to rest on the nightstand beside him.
当然 这是在周三之前
That was, of course, before Wednesday.
到了周三 哈罗德的手表改变了一切
On Wednesday, Harold's wristwatch changed everything.
哦 天啊 你买下了?
Oh, my God, you got it?
我买下了
I got it.
如果有人问哈罗德 他会说
lf one had asked Harold, he would have said...
这个周三正如前面所有周三那样…
...that this particular Wednesday was exactly like all the Wednesdays prior.
他开始按部就班…
And he began it the same way he--
他开始按部就班做往常的事情
And he began it the same way he always did.
喂?
HeIIo?
他开始按部就班做往常的事情
He began it the same way he always did.
当别人…
When others' minds would--
喂?有人吗?
HeIIo? Is someone there?
当别人憧憬着他们即将到来的一天…
When others' minds would fantasize about their upcoming day...
或者甚至要紧握他们梦乡的最后时刻…
...or even try to grip onto the final moments of their dreams...
哈罗德只是数着笔画
...Harold just counted brushstrokes.
好啦 谁刚才说"哈罗德数着笔画?"
AII right, who just said, ''HaroId just counted brushstrokes''?
你怎么知道我在数笔画?
And how do you know I'm counting brushstrokes?
喂?
HeIIo?
真不寻常这简单 朴素…
lt was remarkable how the simple, modest--
真不寻常…
lt was remarkable h--
真不寻常这理所当然的…
lt was remarkable how the simple, modest elements of Harold's life...
简单 朴素的哈罗德的生活
...so often taken for granted...
竟会催生全新的生活
...would become the catalyst for an entirely new life.
哈罗德去赶公车…
Harold ran for the bus...
他那硬皮革鞋发出刺耳的尖叫声
...his stiff leather shoes making a terrible squeaking sound...
就像在沥青上面弯曲了
...as they flexed against the asphalt.
尽管这是不平凡的一天…
And though this was an extraordinary day...
这天哈罗德要永生铭记…
...a day to be remembered for the rest of Harold's life...
他仅以为这是个星期三
...Harold just thought it was a Wednesday.
抱歉 您听到了吗?
I'm sorry, did you hear that?
那个声音 您听到了吗? "哈罗德认为那是个星期三"
The voice. Did you hear it? ''HaroId thought it was a Wednesday''?
别担心 就是星期天
Don't worry, it is Wednesday.
不 您听到了吗? "哈罗德只是认为那是个星期三"
No, no, did you hear it? ''HaroId just thought it was a Wednesday''?
- 谁是哈罗德? - 我就是
-Who's HaroId? -I'm HaroId.
哈罗德 没关系的 今天就是星期三
HaroId, it's okay, it's Wednesday.
不 不 我…
No, no, I....
算了吧
Never mind.
哈罗德工作没法精神集中
Harold couldn't concentrate on his work.
劳驾 哈罗德
Excuse me, HaroId?
他思绪天马行空
His thoughts were scattered. His mind elsewhere.
抱歉
Sorry.
有人要能改正一下… 等一下
Someone here shouId be abIe to fix-- HoId on a second.
嘿 哈罗德 67乘以453是多少?
Hey, HaroId. What's 67 times 453?
当一个同事问他67与453的乘积时…
When a coworker asked the product of 67 and 453...
你知道吗 你说话时我没法思考
You know what? I can't think whiIe you're taIking.
他没想出来
...he drew a blank.
- 什么? - 什么?
-What? -What?
- 哈罗德快速地答道 30351 - 什么?没什么 30351
-Harold quickly answered, ''30,35 1. '' -What? Oh, nothing. 30,351 .
不管答案确实是31305
Despite the answer really being 3 1,305.
等等 等等 是31305 抱歉
Wait, wait, wait, 31 ,305. Sorry.
伙计 我碰到个保险仲裁员
Dude, I just totaIIy caught some insurance adjuster...
说他的喷气雪橇是代步工具
...cIaiming his jet ski as a work vehicIe.
我告诉你…
I'II teII you, it is a shame...
他们不给审计员年终奖可真丢人
...that they don't give out an auditor of the year award.
伙计?
Dude?
你没事吧?
You okay?
戴维 我被跟踪了
Dave, I'm being foIIowed.
你怎么会被跟踪? 你动都没动
How are you being foIIowed? You're not moving.
- 是被一个声音跟踪的 - 什么?
-It's by a voice. -What?
我被一个女人的声音跟踪
I'm being foIIowed by a woman's voice.
好吧
Okay.
她说什么?
What is she saying?
她在叙述
She's narrating.
哈罗德 你在盯着这些盒子 她在说什么?
HaroId, you're staring at boxes, what is she narrating?
不 不 我不整理档案了
No, no, no. I had to stop fiIing.
看 看 听 听
Watch. Watch. Listen. Listen.
文件摩擦文件夹的声音
The sound the paper made against the folder...
与海浪打在沙滩上声音很像
...had the same tone as a wave scraping against sand.
哈罗德想到这个的时候
And when Harold thought about it...
他每天听的海浪的声音
...he listened to enough waves every day...
足够形成深不可测 一望无际的大海了
...to constitute what he imagined to be a deep and endless ocean.
你听到了吗?
Did you hear that?
你是说那文件的声音?
You mean you fiIing?
不 不 那个人声
No, no, no, the voice.
没听见
No.
吓人的是我确实想像到 深不可测 一望无际的大海
Frightening part is sometimes I do imagine a deep and endIess ocean.
什么大海?
What ocean?
有声音形成的… 算了吧
The one made by the sound-- Forget it.
新的帐目 祝你好运
New audits. Have a good day.
谢谢
Thank you.
这有个烤面包师和一个证券交易商
AII right, we got a baker and a securities trader.
也许你该来这个烤面包师
Maybe you shouId take the baker.
- 好吗? - 好的
-Okay? -Okay.
见鬼!见鬼!见鬼!
Damn it! Damn it! Damn it!
- 你这个卑鄙小人 - 我明白
-You miscreant. -I understand.
哦 去死吧 收税员!
Oh, get bent, taxman!
- 收税员! - 收税员!
-Taxman! -Taxman!
收税员!
Taxman!
滚回家去!
Go home!
我们能找个别的地方谈谈吗?
Listen, is there somewhere eIse we couId taIk about this?
不 就在这谈
No. We're gonna taIk about this right here.
好吧 文件上面说你去年只交了一部分税
Okay. It says, the fiIe, that you onIy paid part of your taxes for Iast year.
- 没错 - 看上去只有78%
-That's right. -Looks Iike onIy 7 8 percent.
对
Yep.
你是故意的?
So you did it on purpose?
对
Yep.
那你肯定在等着查你帐了?
So you must have been expecting an audit?
我在等着…
I was expecting a fine...
强有力的申诉
...or a sharp reprimand.
申诉?这可不是寄宿学校 帕斯卡女士
A reprimand? This isn't boarding schooI, Ms. PascaI.
你偷了政府的钱
You stoIe from the government.
不 我没偷政府的钱 我只是没把钱交齐
No, I didn't steaI from the government. I just didn't pay you entireIy.
帕斯卡女士 你不能就这么不交税
Ms. PascaI, you can't just not pay your taxes.
我能
Yes, I can.
除非你想被查账
You can if you wanna get audited.
只要我发现是你来查账 克里克先生
OnIy if I recognize your right to audit me, Mr. Crick.
帕斯卡女士 我就是到这来查账的
Ms. PascaI, I'm right here auditing you.
我现在要核对你过去三年的帐目
Now I have to go over your past three years...
以确认那是仅有的一笔被拖欠的
...to make sure that's aII you haven't paid.
好吧
Fine.
实际上 不怎么好
ActuaIIy, you know, it's not fine.
听着 我很支持整修坑洼路面
Listen, I'm a big supporter of fixing pothoIes...
设立儿童转梯 修建避难所什么的
...and erecting swing sets and buiIding sheIters.
我非常愿意付那部分的税
I am more than happy to pay those taxes.
我只是不怎么支持
I'm just not such a big fan of the percentage...
政府在国家防御 集体财政紧急援助 和竞选自由基金
...that the government uses for nationaI defense...
上面花费的比例
...corporate baiIouts and campaign discretionary funds.
所以我不付那部分税
So I didn't pay those taxes.
我想 实际上…
I think, actuaIIy...
我想发一封信来讨回那部分钱
...I sent a Ietter to that effect with my return.
是不是这封开头是 "亲爱的帝国主义猪"
WouId it be the Ietter that begins, ''Dear ImperiaIist Swine''?
是的
Yes.
帕斯卡女士 你形容的那是无政府状态 你是无政府主义者吗?
Ms. PascaI, what you're describing is anarchy. Are you an anarchist?
- 你是说我是… - 无政府组织成员 对
-You mean am I a member of--? -An anarchist group, yes.
无政府主义者还有组织?
Anarchists have a group?
我想是吧
I beIieve so. Sure.
他们还集合起来?
They assembIe?
我不知道
I don't know.
那样不就有悖初衷了吗?
WouIdn't that compIeteIy defeat the purpose?
哈罗德很难想象帕斯卡女士是革命者
lt was difficult for Harold to imagine Ms. Pascal as a revolutionary.
- 现在不行 - 她那瘦弱的胳膊…
-Not now. -Her thin arms...
- 什么? - 举着反对标语
-What? -...hoisting protest signs.
- 她那纤细的双腿… - 没什么
-Her long shapely legs... -Nothing.
在催泪瓦斯下狂奔
...dashing from tear gas.
哈罗德并不倾于幻想
Harold wasn't prone to fantasies...
所以他尽量保持专业
...and so he tried his best to remain professional.
但是 当然 失败了
But, of course, failed.
他情不自禁地想像着帕斯卡女士…
He couldn't help but imagine Ms. Pascal...
用她那纤纤细手抚摸他的脸庞
...stroking the side of his face with the soft blade of her finger.
他情不自禁地想像她浸在浴缸里
He couldn't help but imagine her immersed in a tub...
修剪双腿上的汗毛
...shaving her legs.
他情不自禁地想像她赤裸的…
And he couldn't help but imagine her naked...
…伸过他的床边 - 克里克先生?
-...stretched across his bed. -Mr. Crick?
- 克里克先生 - 什么事?
-Mr. Crick. -Yes, what is it?
你在盯着我的咪咪
You're staring at my tits.
我?不是吧 我想我没有盯着看
I wa--? I don't think I was. I don't think I wouId do that.
如果我有 我可以向你保证…
If I was, I can assure you...
…这只是美国政府的一个代表
...it was onIy as a representative of the United States government.
对不起 我今天还有事 我星期二再来
Sorry, I'm just having issues today. So I'II be back on Tuesday.
哈罗德突然发现自己在烤包店外面
Harold suddenly found himself beleaguered and exasperated...
…被包围和激怒了 - 闭嘴!
-...outside the bakery... -Shut up!
…诅咒老天无济于事
...cursing the heavens in futility.
不 我没在咒你 你这弱智的声音!
No, I'm not, I'm cursing you, you stupid voice!
闭上嘴 别管我!
So shut up and Ieave me aIone!
嘿 看着点!
Hey, watch it!
打扰了
Excuse me.
你是艾芙小姐吗?
Are you Miss EiffeI?
- 是的 - 太好了
-Yes. -ExceIIent.
我能问问您在做什么吗?
May I ask what you're doing?
研究
Research.
- 哦 能打断一下吗? - 好吧
-Oh, am I interrupting? -Yes.
对不起 我叫彭妮·艾舍
I'm sorry. I'm Penny Escher.
我是你的出版商的助理
I'm the assistant your pubIishers hired.
- 间谍 - 助理
-The spy. -The assistant.
我提供的服务等同于秘书
I provide the same services as a secretary.
我不需要秘书
I don't need a secretary.
那我就要找点别的事情打发时间了
Then I wiII have to find some other way of occupying my time.
就像个秃鹰一样盯着我…
Like watching me Iike a vuIture...
因为出版商认为我有写作障碍 对吗?
...because the pubIishers think I have writer's bIock, right?
你有写作障碍吗?
Do you have writer's bIock?
这是书页吗?
Are these pages?
是信件 写给我的
They're Ietters. To me.
- 你回信吗? - 我不回信
-Are you writing back? -I don't respond to Ietters.
猜这些烟都是你抽的吧
And I suppose you smoked aII these cigarettes?
不 别人抽完放这的
No, they came pre-smoked.
没错 他们说你很有趣
Yeah, they said you were funny.
你怎么看跳楼这种事?
What do you think about Ieaping off a buiIding?
我不考虑跳楼的事情
I don't think about Ieaping off buiIdings.
- 你考虑了 - 不 我尽量想些美好的事情
-Yes, you do. -No. I try to think of nice things.
每个人都考虑跳楼的事情
Everyone thinks about Ieaping off buiIdings.
我肯定不考虑
WeII, I certainIy don't think about Ieaping off of a buiIding.
他们说…
They say--
我从这本无故压抑人的书上读到…
I read this in this fantasticaIIy depressing book.
当你从楼上跳下…
--that when you jump from a buiIding...
实际上很少是撞击力杀死你
...it's rareIy the impact that actuaIIy kiIIs you.
我肯定这书没什么用
WeII, I'm sure it doesn't heIp.
书上有张照片叫做"跳跃着"
There's a photograph in the book caIIed The Leaper.
很老 但很漂亮
It's oId, but it's beautifuI.
在一具跳楼身亡的妇女尸体上方
From above the corpse of a woman who'd just Ieapt to her death.
头部周围都是血 就像光晕…
There's bIood around her head, Iike a haIo...
下面是双腿扭在一起 胳膊像小树枝一样折断
...and her Ieg's buckIed underneath, her arm's snapped Iike a twig...
但是她的表情平静
...but her face is so serene...
很安详
...so at peace.
我想那是因为她死的时候
And I think it's because when she died...
她能感觉到拂面的清风
...she couId feeI the wind against her face.
我不知道怎样杀死哈罗德·克里克 他们就是为这个派你来的吧
I don't know how to kiII HaroId Crick. That's why they sent you.
是的 来帮你
Yes, to heIp you.
你怎样帮我?
How are you gonna heIp me?
你这个从没考虑过跳楼的人?
You, who never thinks of Ieaping off buiIdings?
你能给我什么灵感?
What great inspiration wiII you bestow on me?
我告诉你 你在可敬的"助理"生涯中
I'II teII you, the quaint ideas you've gathered...
积累起来的新奇的想法
...in your adorabIe career as an ''assistant''...
面对杀死一个人这种问题时毫无用处
...are to no avaiI when faced with kiIIing a man.
我明白
I understand.
是吗?我只是不能…
Do you? I can't just--
就我来说…
As much as I wouId Iike to...
我不能简单地把哈罗德·克里克从楼上扔下去
...I cannot simpIy throw HaroId Crick off a buiIding.
艾芙小姐 凯 我做作家助理11年了
Miss EiffeI. Kay. I've been an author's assistant for 1 1 years.
我帮助了超过20个作家 完成了超过35本书
I've heIped more than 20 authors compIete more than 35 books...
从未错过期限
...and I've never missed the deadIine.
我从没有过回到出版商那里多争取时间
And I have never gone back to the pubIisher to ask for more time.
现在我随时供您调遣
Now, I wiII be avaiIabIe to you every minute of every day...
直到最后一个标点写在最后一页纸上
...untiI the finaI punctuation is embedded on the very Iast page.
我不喜欢丝竹乱耳 不能容忍麻醉自我
I do not Iike Ioud music. I do not abide narcotics.
我要高兴地平静地 帮你杀死哈罗德·克里克
And I wiII gIadIy and quietIy heIp you kiII HaroId Crick.
[来自卡利博士 人力资源部] [我们聊聊吧]
我和你的部门有些人唠了唠嗑
I had a very interesting IittIe convo with someone in your section.
是吗?
Yeah?
他们说你感觉有点忽忽悠悠
They said you were feeIing a IittIe wibbIy-wobbIy.
屋里闷太久了?
Catch a IittIe cubicIe fever?
我不知道 我觉得我很好
Oh, I don't know. I think I'm okay.
哈罗德 树不觉得自己是树…
HaroId, a tree doesn't think it's a tree...
尽管就是树
...it is a tree.
为什么哈罗德要和这个人谈话?
Why was Harold talking to this man?
这人是个傻冒
This man was an idiot.
这人用"忽忽悠悠" "唠嗑"这样的词
This man used words like ''wibbly-wobbly'' and ''convo. ''
还解释说树是树
And explained that trees were trees.
树当然是树
Of course trees were trees.
哈罗德知道树是树
Harold knew trees were trees.
我要相信你了 哈罗德
I am going to beIieve you, HaroId.
哈罗德不知道的是
What Harold didn't know was why he couldn't shake...
为何他忘不掉那褐色的气味
...the smell of brownies from his senses.
为何帕斯卡女士 让他指尖颤抖 双唇紧闭
Why Ms. Pascal had made his fingertips quiver and lips go numb.
哈罗德?
HaroId?
抱歉
Yes? Sorry.
怎么了 哈罗德?
What's going on, HaroId?
嗯…
WeII....
没什么 都很好
Nothing. Everything's fine.
听着 根据你的记录…
Listen, according to your records...
你这几年都没休过假
...you haven't taken vacation in a few years now.
去休息休息吧
Let's say you take a IittIe break.
使用点假期
Use some of that vaca time.
嗯 我会考虑一下的
Yeah. I'II think about it.
哈罗德
HaroId.
我真不应该这样做 但…
I'm not reaIIy supposed to do this, but....
哈罗德简单地认为他的手表出故障了
Harold assumed his watch was simply on the fritz...
从没想过它也许想告诉他什么
...and never even considered that it might be trying to tell him something.
实际上 哈罗德从没注意过他的表…
ln fact, Harold had never once paid attention to his watch...
除了看看时间
...other than to find out the time.
老实说 这把他的表逼疯了
And, honestly, it drove his watch crazy.
所以 在这个特别的星期三的傍晚…
And so, on this particular Wednesday evening...
正当哈罗德等公车 他的表…
...as Harold waited for the bus, his watch suddenly...
停了
...stopped.
对不起 有人知道时间吗?
Sorry, does anyone have the time?
- 嗯 我这是6点18 - 谢谢
-Yeah, I got 6:1 8. -Thanks.
这样哈罗德的表把他送上一条不归路
Thus Harold's watch thrust him into the immitigable path of fate.
他毫不知晓这个表面上无害的动作…
Little did he know that this simple, seemingly innocuous act...
会导致他即将到来的死亡
...would result in his imminent death.
什么?什么?
What? What?
嘿!哈罗!
Hey! HeIIo?
什么!
What?
为什么?
Why?
为什么我会死?
Why my death?
哈罗!
HeIIo!
劳驾!
Excuse me!
什么时候?
When?
有多近?
How imminent?
好吧 你在哪?
Okay, where are you?
"哈罗德刷他32颗牙齿72遍"
''HaroId wouId brush his 32 teeth 72 times.''
你为什么不说话? 我听得见你
Why won't you say anything? I heard you.
"这会导致他即将到来的死亡"
''That wouId resuIt in his imminent death.''
我听见你了!
I heard you!
快出来 你这弱智声音
Come on, you stupid voice.
"哈罗德狂暴地抓起他的台灯
''HaroId franticaIIy grabbed his Iamp.
哈罗德愤怒地 无缘由地 把它扔了出去
HaroId, incensed, shook the heII out of it for no apparent reason!
把它摔在地上 一个劲地踢
And smashed it on the ground, kicking it repeatedIy!
哈罗德拿起他的面巾纸盒 扔到屋子另一边…
HaroId took his KIeenex box, threw it across the room...
然后对着衣橱爆发了
...then stormed the cIoset!''
来啊 说话啊
Come on. Say something.
说话啊!
Something. Say something!
Say something!
"哈罗德 发狂的…"
''HaroId, distraught....''
天啊
God.
"哈罗德 发狂的…"
''HaroId, distraught....''
"哈罗德…"
''HaroId....''
我恐怕您所描述的是精神分裂症
l'm afraid what you're describing is schizophrenia.
不 不 不是精神分裂症 只是我耳边有个声音
No. No. It's not schizophrenia. It's just a voice in my head.
我是说 那个声音什么都没让我做
I mean, the voice isn't teIIing me to do anything.
只是在说我做了什么
It's teIIing me what I've aIready done.
用词准确而丰富
AccurateIy and with a better vocabuIary.
克里克先生 您听到一个声音对您讲话
Mr. Crick, you have a voice speaking to you.
不 不是对我讲话 而是说着我的事情
No, not to me, about me.
我不知何故卷进了什么故事中
I'm somehow invoIved in some sort of story.
就像我是我自己生活中一个角色
Like I'm a character in my own Iife.
但问题是那个声音来来往往
But the probIem is that the voice comes and goes.
好像故事其它部分并没告诉我
Like there are other parts of the story not being toId to me...
我要尽快弄清楚其他部分
...and I need to find out what those other parts are before it's too Iate.
在那故事以你死亡作为结局之前
Before the story concIudes with your death.
是的
Yes.
克里克先生 我不想给人打击
Mr. Crick, I hate to sound Iike a broken record...
但这就是精神分裂症
...but that's schizophrenia.
您听着不是给人打击 但这不是精神分裂症
You don't sound Iike a broken record, but it's just not schizophrenia.
要是我说的没错呢?
What if what I said was true?
假设我就是故事的一部分 有个讲述者
HypotheticaIIy speaking, if I was part of a story, a narrative...
即使是仅存在于我的脑中
...even if it was onIy in my mind...
您建议我怎么做呢?
...what wouId you suggest that I do?
我建议您按方抓药
I wouId suggest you take prescribed medication.
除此之外的
Other than that.
我不知道
I don't know.
我觉得我要把你送到认识作家的人那
I suppose I wouId send you to see someone who knows about Iiterature.
好吧
Okay.
这是个不错的主意
Yeah. That's a good idea.
谢谢
Thank you.
那么您就是那位打电话给我说 关于讲述者事情的那位先生
So you're the gentIeman who caIIed me about the narrator.
- 是的 - 那个讲述者说您会死去
-Yes. -This narrator says you're gonna die.
是的
Yes.
- 您还能活多长时间? - 我不知道
-How Iong has it given you to Iive? -I don't know.
真讽刺 你随时会挂掉
Dramatic irony. It'II fuck you every time.
- 所以你很抓狂吧? - 嗯…
-So you crazy or what? -WeII--
你被允许和疯狂的人说这个吗?
Are you aIIowed to say that to crazy peopIe?
- 我不知道 - 走廊里…
-I don't know. -Oh, weII. How many stairs...
…有多少级台阶? - 什么?
-...in the haIIway out there? -What?
我们在走路的时候你就在数 对吧?
You were counting them as we waIked, weren't you?
没有
No.
当然有 你在哪家银行工作?
Of course. What bank do you work at?
不是银行 我是国税局审计员
No bank. IRS agent.
- 结婚了? - 没
-Married? -No.
结过吗?
Ever?
曾和一个审计员订婚了 然后她甩了我去找一个保险统计师了
Engaged to an auditor. She Ieft me for an actuary.
- 真让人伤心 自己住着? - 对
-How heartbreaking. Live aIone? -Yes.
- 养宠物吗? - 没
-Any pets? -No.
- 有朋友吗? - 没 嗯 戴维 工作上的
-Friends? -No. WeII, Dave at work.
我明白了 那个叙述者 他是什么声音?
I see. The narrator, exactIy what does he sound Iike?
是个女人
It's a woman.
女人
A woman.
- 熟悉的女人? - 不是
-Is it a famiIiar woman? -No.
你认识的?
Someone you know?
不是
No.
你有时间数清厕所里的瓷砖吗?
Did you have enough time to count the tiIes in the bathroom?
我没数瓷砖
I wasn't counting the tiIes.
- 喝咖啡吗? - 不 谢谢
-Coffee? -No, thank you.
- 肯定? - 是的
-Sure? -Yes.
那么这个女人 她的声音 告诉你你会死去?
So this woman, the voice, toId you you're gonna die?
她不是告诉我 他不知道我能听见她
She didn't teII me. She doesn't know I can hear her.
- 但她说出来了 - 是的
-But she said it. -Yes.
而且你相信她
And you beIieved her.
有些事情上她是不对的
She's been right about a few other things.
- 比如? - 我对工作的感觉
-Such as? -How I feIt about work.
- 你不喜欢你的工作? - 是的
-You disIike your work? -Yes.
还不是世界上最有洞察力的声音 是吧?
WeII, not the most insightfuI voice in the worId, is it?
美国人厌恶列表上的第一条：工作
First thing on a Iist of what Americans hate: work.
第二条 交通；第三条 丢失的袜子 明白我的话吗?
Second, traffic. Third, missing socks. See what I'm saying?
有点
Sort of.
我告诉你你会死去 你信吗?
I toId you you were gonna die, you beIieve me?
- 不信 - 为什么?
-No. -Why?
我不认识你
I don't know you.
- 但你也不认识那个叙述者 - 嗯…
-But you don't know this narrator. -WeII....
- 好吧 克里克先生 我帮不了你 - 为什么?
-Okay, Mr. Crick, I can't heIp you. -Why?
我不是疯狂事情的专家 我是文学史方面的专家
WeII, I'm not an expert in crazy, I'm an expert in Iiterature theory.
我要告诉你 到目前为止…
And I gotta teII you, thus far...
没有一件关于你的作品
...there doesn't seem to be a singIe Iiterary thing about you.
我不怀疑你听见一个声音 但是不大可能有个叙述者…
I don't doubt you hear a voice, but it couIdn't possibIy be a narrator...
因为 老实说 这没什么可讲述的
...because, frankIy, there doesn't seem to be much to narrate.
除此之外 这学期我教5门课
Beside that, this semester I'm teaching five courses.
带两个博士生
I'm mentoring two doctoraI candidates...
我还是游泳池的教师救生员
...and I'm the facuIty Iifeguard at the pooI.
- 我只是认为您能… - 也许你应该记日记
-I just thought you couId possibIy-- -Perhaps you shouId keep a journaI.
把她说的记下来
Write down what she said or something.
我只能建议这些了
That's aII I can suggest.
我记不全了 我只能想记住
I can bareIy remember it aII. I just remember:
"他毫不知晓这个简单看似无害的动作…
''LittIe did he know that this simpIe, seemingIy innocuous act...
将会导致他即将到来的死亡"
...wouId Iead to his imminent death.''
- 什么? - "他毫不知晓这个…"
-What? -''LittIe did he know that this--''
- 你说"他毫不知晓" - 是的
-Did you say, ''IittIe did he know''? -Yes.
我写过关于"他毫不知晓"方面的论文
I've written papers on ''IittIe did he know.''
我曾经教过一节课 里面讲"他毫不知晓"
I used to teach a cIass based on ''IittIe did he know.''
我是说 我开过"他毫不知晓"的研讨会
I mean, I once gave an entire seminar on ''IittIe did he know.''
见鬼了 哈罗德
Son of a bitch, HaroId.
"他毫不知晓"意思是有些是他不知道的
''LittIe did he know'' means there's something he doesn't know...
意思是有些是你不知道的 明白吗?
...that means there's something you don't know. Did you know that?
- 我要你周五再来 - 好的
-I want you to come back Friday. -Okay.
不 "即将到来" 有可能你周五就死了
No, ''imminent,'' you couId be dead by Friday.
明天9:45过来
Come back tomorrow at 9:45.
10秒钟之前你还说你不会帮我
Ten seconds ago you said you wouIdn't heIp me.
这是很有启迪作用的10秒钟 哈罗德
It's been a very reveaIing 1 0 seconds, HaroId.
哈罗德陷入沉思
Harold was deep in thought.
就在那短短的一瞬 从伯恩大道到欧几里德大街…
For a few, brief moments, from Born Boulevard to Euclid Avenue...
所有的算术 所有的规则
...all the calculations and all the rules...
所有哈罗德精确的人生都烟消云散
...and all the precision of Harold's life just faded away.
那时候安娜·帕斯卡出现在那个地方
How perfect then that in this space...
是多么完美的事
...Ana Pascal would appear.
帕斯卡女士
Ms. PascaI.
帕斯卡女士 我是哈罗德·克里克 国税局的
Ms. PascaI, it's HaroId Crick from the IRS.
劳驾
Excuse me.
- 嗨 - 嗨
-Hi. -Hi.
- 你要坐吗? - 不了
-WouId you Iike a seat? -Nope.
还有11站呢
There's 1 1 open ones.
无所谓
I don't care.
对不起
Sorry about that.
你好吗?
How are you?
我烦死了 我在被查账
I'm Iousy. I'm being audited.
当然
Of course.
还面对一个恶心的家伙
By a reaI creep too.
我想我欠你一个道歉
I think I owe you an apoIogy.
- 真的? - 国税局审计员…
-ReaIIy? -IRS agents...
我们上岗前要经过严格的能力测验
...we're given rigorous aptitude tests before we can work.
对你很不幸 我们没测验策略 以及服务态度
UnfortunateIy for you, we aren't tested on tact or good manners...
所以…我道歉
...so I apoIogize.
我那时轻浮地盯着你看
I ogIed you.
对不起
Sorry.
没什么 道歉接受了
Okay, apoIogy accepted.
但仅仅是因为你口吃
But onIy because you stammered.
那么你是常坐公车了?
So you're a frequenter of the metropoIitan transit authority too?
不 我只是迟到了
No. I'm just Iate.
要去进行大抗议?
Big fIag-burning to get to?
实际上…
ActuaIIy...
这是我每周的小活动 刺绣小组
...it's my weekIy eviI-conspiracy and needIepoint group.
你想来吗?
You wanna come?
我把顶针和社会主义阅读材料 落在家里了
I Ieft my thimbIes and sociaIist reading materiaI at home.
所以…
So....
哈罗德紧张地闲聊着…
Harold nervously made small talk.
你牙齿很整齐
You have very straight teeth.
没话找话
Very small talk.
谢谢 那是真的
Thanks. They're reaI.
哈罗德快速地计算着
Harold quickly calculated the odds of making an ass of himself...
他坐在那聊天的时间里冒傻气的几率
...in ratio to the amount of time he stayed to chat.
我到站了
This is my stop. I shouId go.
…他对与帕斯卡女士的艳遇 - 再见
-He was elated and surprised... -See you soon.
又惊又喜
...by his somewhat flirtatious encounter with Ms. Pascal.
高兴得以致于他早下车了27个街区
So elated that he exited the Transit Authority bus...
不得不后面靠步行了
...a good 2 7 blocks too early and would now have to walk.
- 你还没倒下呢 - 没错
-''You ain't down yet. '' -That's right.
告诉我们 "你没有我任何把柄"的意思 埃莫特·科尔?
Tell us, what is You Ain't Got Nothin' On Me about, Emmett Cole?
那是什么意思?
What does this mean?
那就是谁 纵观全球 做不同的事情…
Well, it's about being around in the world, doing different things...
…做你想做的 - 进来
-...doing what you wanna do.... -Come in.
克里克先生 请进 请进
Mr. Crick. Come in, come in. PIease.
你好吗?
How are you?
我很好 实际上
I'm fine, actuaIIy.
你可以把那个关上了
You can turn that off.
看上去我们的叙述者还没杀死你
Looks Iike our narrator hasn't kiIIed you quite yet.
- 还没 - 不错 请坐
-No, not yet. -Good, great. Have a seat.
- 数外面楼梯数了吗? - 没
-Count the stairs outside? -No.
当然没有 我设计了个测验…
Course not. I've devised a test--
有23个题目
How exciting is that? --of 23 questions...
我想能帮着揭开更多 关于这个叙述者的真相
...which I think might heIp uncover more truths about this narrator.
- 现在 霍华德… - 是哈罗德
-Now, Howard.... -HaroId.
哈罗德 这可能看上去很傻 但是你的坦诚是非常重要的
HaroId. These may seem siIIy, but your candor is paramount.
好的
Okay.
那么
So.
我们知道这是个女人的声音 这个故事涉及到你的死亡
We know it's a woman's voice, the story invoIves your death...
现代的 英语的
...it's modern, it's in EngIish.
我猜这个作者对这城市的了解很浅显
I'm assuming the author has a cursory knowIedge of the city.
- 当然 - 好的
-Sure. -Okay, good.
问题一
Question one:
最近有人在你家留下礼物吗?
''Has anyone recentIy Ieft any gifts outside your home?''
什么都算 口香糖?钱?
Anything? Gum? Money?
- 大个的木马? - 什么?
-A Iarge wooden horse? -I'm sorry?
- 回答问题 - 没有
-Just answer the question. -No.
你有没发现自己有解决神秘谋杀的倾向…
''Do you find yourseIf incIined to soIve murder mysteries...
那是在大的 豪华的房间里 让我说完
...in Iarge, Iuxurious homes to which--?'' Let me finish.
你也许是被邀请到那去的
''To which you may or may not have been invited?''
不 不 不 没有
No. No, no, no.
好的 你觉得你有多大可能…
AII right. On a scaIe of one to 1 0...
被刺杀 从1到10
...what wouId you consider the IikeIihood you might be assassinated?
刺杀?
Assassinated?
1是最不可能 10是最可能
One being very unIikeIy, 1 0 being expecting it around every corner.
- 我不知道 - 好吧 我换个说法
-I have no idea-- -Okay. Let me rephrase.
你觉得你是个王吗?
Are you the king of anything?
- 比如 ? - 随便啦
-Like what? -Anything.
比如当地保龄球馆球道之王
King of the Ianes at the IocaI bowIing aIIey.
球道之王?
''King of the Ianes''?
- 球道之王 矮人之王 - 矮人之王?
-King of the Ianes. King of the troIIs. -''King of the troIIs''?
对 那是在你家地板下的神秘土地上
Yes. A cIandestine Iand found underneath your fIoorboards.
- 随便什么 - 没有
-Anything. -No.
不 太荒谬了
No. That's ridicuIous.
同意 但我们从荒谬开始后退
Agreed. But Iet's start with ridicuIous and move backwards.
有没有你的一部分曾经是 别的东西的一部分?
Now, was any part of you at one time part of something eIse?
比如我长着别人的胳膊
Like do I have someone eIse's arms?
嗯 有没可能曾经你是石头…
WeII, is it possibIe at one time that you were made of stone...
木头 碱液 尸体的各个部分…
...wood, Iye, varied corpse parts...
或者是希伯来长者用泥土做成的?
...or earth made hoIy by rabbinicaI eIders?
没有 听着 抱歉 这些问题有什么关系?
No. Look.... I'm sorry. What do these questions have to do with anything?
这是找到你是处在哪个故事中
The onIy way to find out what story you're in...
或是没处在哪个故事中的唯一方法
...is to determine what stories you're not in.
尽管看上去奇怪 我已经排除了 一半希腊文学
Odd as it may seem, I've just ruIed out haIf of Greek Iiterature...
7则神话传说 10条中国寓言…
...seven fairy taIes, 1 0 Chinese fabIes...
最后确定你不是哈姆雷特王…
...and determined concIusiveIy that you are not King HamIet...
斯科特·芬奇（杀死一只知更鸟中的人物） 马普尔小姐（克里斯蒂侦探小说中的人物）
...Scout Finch, Miss MarpIe...
科学怪人的怪物或者是希伯来魔像
...Frankenstein's monster, or a goIem.
你放心自己不是魔像?
Aren't you reIieved to know you're not a goIem?
是的 我放心我不是魔像
Yes, I am reIieved to know that I am not a goIem.
很好
Good.
你有没有魔力?
Do you have magicaI powers?
我能问问我们在干什么吗?
May I ask what we're doing out here?
- 想像汽车事故 - 明白了
-We're imagining car wrecks. -I see.
我们就不能在屋里想像?
And we can't imagine car wrecks inside?
不行
No.
你知不知道41%的交通事故
Did you know that 41 percent of accidents...
是发生在恶劣天气下的?
...occur in times of incIement weather?
90%的肺炎也是
So do 90 percent of pneumonia cases.
真的?肺炎 那倒是个有趣的死法
ReaIIy? Pneumonia. That's an interesting way to die.
但是哈罗德怎么感染上肺炎呢?
But how wouId HaroId catch pneumonia?
今天你写了新的内容吗?
Have you written anything new today?
没有
No.
有没有读我推荐的诗 做个词语列表
Did you read the poems I suggested, or make a Iist of words...
买新的打字纸什么的?
...buy new typing paper, anything?
都没做
No, none of it.
坐在雨里写不了书
Sitting in the rain won't write books.
那倒是恰恰说明你对写书了解多少
WeII, that iIIustrates exactIy how much you know about writing books.
这是什么?
What's this?
尼古丁贴片上的文学
It's Iiterature on the nicotine patch.
我不需要尼古丁贴片 我抽烟
I don't need a nicotine patch, Penny. I smoke cigarettes.
这也许有用
WeII, it may heIp.
有用?什么用?
May heIp? HeIp what?
什么用 彭妮?能写小说?
HeIp what, Penny? HeIp write a noveI?
能救你的命
May heIp save your Iife.
我不做救命的事情
I'm not in the business of saving Iives.
实际上 正相反
In fact, just the opposite.
- 你最喜欢的词是什么? - 整数
-''What's your favorite word?'' -Integer.
很好 很好
Good, good, good.
你有什么渴望的事情吗?
''Do you aspire to anything?''
- 没有 - 攻占俄罗斯?
-No. -Conquer Russia?
- 赢得吹口哨比赛? - 没有
-Win a whistIing contest? -No.
哈罗德 你必须有点野心
HaroId, you must have some ambition.
- 我不这么看 - 埋在心底的梦想 想想
-I don't think so. -Some underIying dream. Think.
嗯…
WeII...
我一直想我的生活更音乐一些
...I've aIways wanted my Iife to be more musicaI.
- 就像《西城故事》? - 不是
-Like West Side Story? -No.
- 就像… - 什么?
-Like.... -What?
我一直想学弹吉他
WeII, I've aIways wanted to Iearn to pIay the guitar.
好的
Okay.
最后一件要确定的事是
The Iast thing to determine concIusiveIy...
你是在喜剧还是在悲剧中
...is whether you're in a comedy or a tragedy.
引用伊塔洛·卡尔维诺的话说： （意大利作家）
To quote ItaIo CaIvino:
"所有故事的终极含义有两方面：
''The uItimate meaning to which aII stories refer has two faces:
生命的连续性以及死亡的必然性"
The continuity of Iife, the inevitabiIity of death.''
悲剧里你死了 喜剧里你结婚了
Tragedy, you die. Comedy, you get hitched.
大多数的漫画英雄
Most comic heroes faII in Iove with peopIe...
爱上了故事一开始就出场的人物
...introduced after the story has begun.
通常人们开始讨厌那个英雄
UsuaIIy peopIe who hate the hero initiaIIy.
然而我没法想像人们讨厌你你 哈罗德
AIthough I can't imagine anyone hating you, HaroId.
希尔伯特教授 我是国税局审计员
Professor HiIbert, I'm an IRS agent.
大家都讨厌我
Everyone hates me.
没错 很好
Right, right. Good.
你最近有没有遇到什么人特别地恨你?
Have you met anyone recentIy who might Ioathe the very core of you?
我正在查一个女人的帐 她让我滚蛋
I just started auditing a woman who toId me to get bent.
听上去像个喜剧
WeII, that sounds Iike a comedy.
尽量去发展一下
Try to deveIop that.
四份都要?
Four of these?
我这个没蜂蜜了
You know, I didn't get my honey, honey.
露露 你能为拉里灌满蜂蜜吗?
LuIu, can you refiII the honey for Larry? Quarters aIso?
好孩子
That's my good boy.
我加些橡子
I'm adding some acorns.
克拉克先生
Mr. Crick.
你来得真早 肯定要去勒索很多人
You're here earIy. Must have a Iot of peopIe to extort.
不 不 只有你
No. No, just you.
[左面：喜剧；右面：悲剧]
- 枝茶和香蕉面包 - 是的 夫人
-Twig tea and banana bread. -Yes, ma'am.
实际上 只用一天就确定你只欠那22%了
ActuaIIy, it shouId onIy take the day to make sure 22 percent is aII you owe.
不管是百分之多少我都不会交钱的
WeII, I won't be paying no matter the percentage, Mr. Crick.
我明白 但是那百分比决定 你的牢房有多大
No, I know. But the percent determines how big your ceII is.
你可以叫我哈罗德
You know, you can caII me HaroId.
我知道 但我不想这么叫
Yeah, I know. But I don't want to.
这是给拉蒙那的
This is for Ramona, honey.
- 哦 谢谢 - 不客气
-Oh, thank you. -You're very weIcome.
那是什么?你在记什么?
What is that? What are you marking?
哦 没什么
Oh, this is nothing.
我们何不从你的备份文件
Why don't we start with your backup documents...
以及过去三年来的收据开始呢
...and the receipts for the past three years.
当然
Sure.
这是什么?
What's this?
- 我的单子 - 什么?
-My fiIes. -What?
我的税单
My tax fiIes.
你就这样保管你的税单?
You keep your fiIes Iike this?
不 实际上我是很挑剔的
No, actuaIIy I'm quite fastidious.
我把它们放在这盒子里 就是为了麻烦麻烦你的
I put them in this box just to screw with you.
- 嗨 - 嗨 你好啊
-Hi. -Hi. How are you?
这个怎么样 阿鲁巴岛的
So how was it? Aruba.
帕斯卡女士 我能就这个收据问你点问题吗?
Ms. PascaI? Can I just ask you a question about this receipt?
- 太棒了 - 我只想知道这个9是不是7
-It was fantastic. -Just wondering if this nine is a seven.
- 你做什么去了? - 我把皮肤晒成漂亮的褐色
-And what did you do? -I got a beautifuI tan.
- 我猜这就是7吧 - 我是说 我感觉压力得到了释放
-I'm just gonna guess it's a seven. -I mean, I feeI stress-free.
要帮忙吗?
Do you need heIp with that?
走到天堂 我见到了总统
--waIk to heaven. I see the president.
- 是税务检查员啊 检查员先生 你好 - 你好
-It's the taxman. HeIIo, Mr. Taxman. -Yeah.
- 你可以叫我哈罗德 - 好的
-You can caII me HaroId. -Okay.
- 进行得怎么样? - 很好
-How the numbers going? -Pretty good.
- 找到那22%了? - 22%?
-Gonna find that 22 percent? -22 percent?
22 11乘以2 都是素数
Twenty-two, 1 1 times 2. It's prime numbers.
- 你要收卫生间的税吗? - 不收
-You gonna tax the bathroom? -No, I'm not gonna tax the bathroom.
- 那我能用一下吗? - 用吧
-CouId I use the bathroom, then? -Go for it.
好的 我要去上卫生间了 回见
Okay. I wanna use the bathroom. Bye now.
回见
Bye-bye.
晚安
WeII, good night.
要一块曲奇吗?
You want a cookie?
不了
Oh, no.
吃吧 又热又甜 刚出炉的
Come on. They're warm and gooey. They're fresh out of the oven.
我不喜欢曲奇
No, I don't Iike cookies.
你不喜欢曲奇?
You don't Iike cookies?
- 你怎么回事? - 我不知道
-What's wrong with you? -I don't know.
- 大家都喜欢曲奇 - 我知道
-Everybody Iikes cookies. -No, I know.
我是说 你经历糟糕的一天后
I mean, after a reaIIy awfuI, no-good day...
你妈妈不给你做点牛奶曲奇吗?
...didn't your mama ever make you miIk and cookies?
我妈妈不烤面包
No. My mother didn't bake.
我只吃过商店买的
The onIy cookies I ever had were store-bought.
好吧 请坐
Okay. Sit down.
- 不 我… - 不
-No, I'm-- -No.
坐下
Sit down.
现在…
Now...
吃一块曲奇
...eat a cookie.
我真的不能吃…
I reaIIy can't.
克拉克先生 这真是糟糕的一天
Mr. Crick, it was a reaIIy awfuI day.
我明白 我很肯定
I know, I made sure of it.
所以 拿起一块曲奇…
So pick up the cookie...
蘸一点牛奶…
...dip it in the miIk...
吃下去
...and eat it.
这真是非常非常上佳的曲奇
That's a reaIIy, reaIIy good cookie.
那你是什么时候决定要当面包师的?
So when did you decide to become a baker?
- 大学时候 - 哦 就像是烹调大学?
-In coIIege. -Oh, Iike a cooking coIIege?
我实际上上的是哈佛法学院
I went to Harvard Law actuaIIy.
- 哦 抱歉 我想当然地认为… - 没 没什么 我没念完
-Oh, I'm sorry, I just assumed it was-- -No. No, it's fine. I didn't finish.
- 发生了什么事吗? - 没有
-Did something happen? -No.
我是刚好被录取的 只差一点点
I was bareIy accepted. I mean, reaIIy bareIy.
他们唯一录取我的理由是我的小论文
The onIy reason they Iet me come was because of my essay.
我要如何用我的学位开创更美好的世界
How I was gonna make the worId a better pIace with my degree.
总之 我们要参与那些学习活动
Anyway, we wouId have to participate in these study sessions...
我的同学们还有我 有时要一整夜
...my cIassmates and I, sometimes aII night Iong.
所以我就烤点面包 这样大家就不会饿了
And so I'd bake so no one wouId go hungry whiIe we worked.
有时我在宿舍一烤就是一下午
Sometimes I wouId bake aII afternoon in the kitchen in the dorm...
然后我就把我的成果拿到学习小组…
...and then I'd bring my IittIe treats to the study groups...
大家很喜欢
...and peopIe Ioved them.
吃吧
Eat.
我做了麦片曲奇 奶油花生长条面包
I made oatmeaI cookies, peanut-butter bars...
…黑巧克力澳洲坚果楔形蛋糕
...dark-chocoIate macadamia-nut wedges.
大家吃了很高兴
And everyone wouId eat and stay happy...
学习更努力 考试成绩更好
...and study harder and do better on the tests.
越来越多的人来到学习小组…
More and more peopIe started coming to the study groups...
我就得多做几份…
...and I'd bring more snacks.
我一直在寻找新的食谱…
I was aIways Iooking for better and better recipes...
后来又有了意大利干酪杏仁面包…
...untiI soon it was ricotta cheese and apricot croissants...
咖啡杏仁长条面包
...and mocha bars with an aImond gIaze...
桃味酥皮柠檬软面包
...and Iemon chiffon cake with zesty peach icing.
最后学期末小组里有27个成员
And at the end of the semester I had 2 7 study partners...
8本期刊上贴满了食谱
...eight Mead journaIs fiIIed with recipes...
我平均成绩是D
...and a D average.
所以我退学了
So I dropped out.
我明白如果我想创立更美好的世界
I figured if I was gonna make the worId a better pIace...
我就用曲奇
...I wouId do it with cookies.
你喜欢吗?
You Iike them?
喜欢
I do.
我很高兴
I'm gIad.
感谢你执意要我吃
Thank you for forcing me to eat them.
别客气
You're weIcome.
我该走了 谢谢你的曲奇
I shouId go. Oh, thank you. For the cookies, I mean.
- 你为何不拿回家去? - 哦 不了
-Why don't you take them home? -Oh, no.
- 哦 拿去吧 - 真的不了
-Oh, come on. -No, reaIIy, pIease.
- 不 拿去吧 真的 - 真的真的不了
-No, reaIIy, pIease. -No, no, no. ReaIIy, pIease.
我很想拿去 但我不能
I wouId Iike to, but I can't.
- 不能? - 我是说…
-You can't? -No, no, I mean--
看 这就算礼物了…
Because, see, it constitutes a gift.
实际上 我连那些都不该吃
ActuaIIy I shouIdn't have even had those other ones, so....
没什么 我不会告诉别人的
Okay. WeII, I'm not gonna teII anyone.
- 我知道 但是如果你… - 我不会的
-No. I know, but if you did.... -WeII, I'm not going to.
我知道 但如果你…
I know, but if you did--
- 怎么 你以为我要去… - 不 不 我买下来吧
-What, you think I'm gonna caII the--? -No, no. I'II purchase them.
我很高兴能买下来 多少钱?
I'm happy to purchase them. How's that?
这样就没问题了
And then there are no issues.
- 怎么? - 没事
-What? -No.
- 求求你 - 只是…
-PIease. -Just....
- 我为何不能… - 回家吧
-Why don't I just--? -Go home.
真的 不是大事情
ReaIIy, it's not a big deaI.
回家去
Go home.
好吧
Okay.
你是不是…
Did you...?
为我烤的曲奇?
You baked those cookies for me, didn't you?
你只想做得好点 而我完全搞砸了
You were just trying to be nice and I totaIIy bIew it.
说这些可能你不明白
This may sound Iike gibberish to you...
但我想我是在悲剧里
...but I think I'm in a tragedy.
希尔伯特教授 我在喜剧悲剧的事情上完全失败了
Professor HiIbert, I've totaIIy faiIed at the comedy-tragedy thing.
实际上 我觉得她更不怎么喜欢我了
In fact, I think she Iikes me even Iess.
- 我知道 很不错 - 什么意思?
-I know, it's great. -What do you mean?
你已经完全证明了别的事情
You've proved something eIse entireIy.
那个声音似乎是决定于你的行动的
The voice seems to be dependent on actions you take.
你对了表 它就说你对了表
You reset your watch, it says you reset your watch.
你乘公车 它就说你乘公车
You ride a bus, it says you ride the bus.
你刷牙 它就说你刷牙
You brush your teeth, it says you brush your teeth.
可能是你自己让这个故事永远进行下去
It may be that you yourseIf are perpetuating the story.
- 所以我建议我们试点别的 - 比如?
-So I suggest we try something eIse. -Like what?
- 什么都不做 - 那帕斯卡女士怎么办?
-Try nothing. Nothing. -What about Ms. PascaI?
- 忘了她 - 忘了她?
-Forget her. -Forget her?
除了数字以外 我只想着她了
Other than numbers, she's aII I think about.
哈罗德 如果你想活着 就得试点别的
HaroId, if you wanna stay aIive, you'II try something eIse.
- 什么都不做? - 对
-That something being nothing? -Nothing, exactIy.
- 都不做? - 我再解释一下
-Nothing? -Let me expIain this again.
有些情节是靠外在的事情或危机发展的
Some pIots are moved forward by externaI events and crises.
另一些是靠角色本身
Others are moved forward by the characters themseIves.
如果我穿过这扇门 情节就发展了
If I go through that door, the pIot continues.
发生的就是我穿过门后来的故事 如果我就待在这…
The story of me through the door. If I stay here...
情节就没法发展 故事就结束了
...the pIot can't move forward, the story ends.
而且如果我待在这 我就迟到了
AIso if I stay here, I'm Iate.
- 明天什么都别做 - 都别做?
-Don't do anything tomorrow. -Nothing?
待在家 别接电话 别开门 别刷牙
Stay home. Don't answer the phone, open the door, brush your teeth.
- 那工作怎么办? - 打电话给他们
-What about work? -CaII them.
- 告诉他们你不去了 - 不去上班?
-TeII them you're not coming. -Don't go to work?
别做任何让情节发展的事情
Don't do anything that may move the pIot forward.
相反 我们看看情节能否找上门来
Instead, Iet's see if the pIot finds you.
马沙尔 你没蹬脚
MarshaII, you're not kicking.
当然这些傻冒只了解这个：
--certain that these geese have never known any home but this one:
波兰东部的一片小湖
A small lake in Eastern Poland.
来自临近工厂的污染正慢慢地杀死…
Pollution from a nearby factory is slowly killing...
小鱼和昆虫这些其他动物的食物
...the small fish and insects on which these creatures feed.
把鸟类移到其他水域的行动都失败了
All attempts to move the birds to similar bodies of water have failed.
也许是熟悉感让它们留在这
Perhaps it is the familiarity alone that keeps them here.
或许是它们不愿意失去
Or perhaps it's an unwillingness to lose the collective memory...
对湖边美丽的小山的回忆
...of the once-beautiful hills that surround the lake.
很快招潮蟹就意识到
And it takes only seconds for the fiddler crabs to realize...
它们曾经害怕的禽鸟
...that the wader they might once have feared...
现在成为了它们的美食
...has now become their prey.
那受伤的鸟知道自己的命运
The wounded bird knows its fate.
它绝望的挣扎
lts desperate attempts to escape...
只能强调它无望的处境
...only underscore the hopelessness of its plight.
灵长目那深情忧郁的眼睛 将先被挖去…
The primates' sad, soulful eyes will be the first to be plucked out...
然后卖给世界上的化妆品公司…
...then sold to cosmetic companies around the world...
用来测试染眉毛油和人造眼泪
...for use in the testing of mascara and artificial tears.
接下来 猴子的毛皮从它们柔软的 身躯上剥下
Next, the monkeys' fur will be stripped away from their limp corpses...
织在一起做成枕头和围巾
...and sewn together to form pillows and comforters.
斑马先生想要美美地喝上一口
Mr. Zebra thought he was gonna take a nice drink.
但你永远不知道
But you never know who's gonna eat...
你在大自然的餐厅中用餐时谁要去下嘴
...when you're dining at Mother Nature's restaurant.
那很疼的 这秃鹰想要
That's gotta hurt. What does this bald eagle wanna serve...
用着芸豆和红葡萄酒招待什么呢?
...with some kidney beans and a fine Chianti?
是美洲鳗 又一下
lt's an eel. And again:
看上去像年长的鳄鱼先生想要吃点羚羊
Looks like old Mr. Crocodile wanted some antelope...
以缓解鳄鱼的咸味
...to clear that salty zebra from his palate.
先生们 为这个赌一把吧
Here's a struggle betting gentlemen have been known to put money on.
当猫鼬遭遇眼镜蛇的时候谁会胜利
When a mongoose encounters a cobra it's hard to know who's gonna win.
但是这次看上去是眼镜蛇了
But this time it looks like it's...the cobra...
它在用力挤压猫鼬
...who's putting the squeeze on the mongoose!
但是别急着收筹码 先生们
But don't cash in your chips just yet, gentlemen...
因为现在是猫鼬取得了胜利!
...because now it's the mongoose who holds the winning card!
嘿!嘿!
Hey! Hey!
嘿!嘿!嘿!你们在干什么?
Hey, hey, hey! What are you doing?!
- 我的老天爷 - 这到底怎么回事?
-HoIy crapping heII. -What the heII is that?
- 停下起重机 停下 - 停下起重机!
-Stop the crane. Stop it. -Stop the crane!
- 嘿 - 嘿 你们在干什么?
-Hey. -Hey, what are you doing?
我们?你在干什么?
Us? What are you doing?
我在看电视
I was watching TV.
- 我们要铲平这片地方 - 你们疯了吗?我住在这!
-WeII, we're demoIishing this pIace. -Are you nuts? I Iive here!
- 这是电视吗? - 是的 是电视 我的电视!
-Is that a TV? -Yes, that's a TV! It's my TV!
- 你的电视怎么到这来了? - 我说了 我住在这 笨蛋!
-WeII, what's your TV doing in there? -I said I Iive here, stupid!
我的家当都在这!
It's where I keep my stuff!
我的名字在那蜂鸣器上面! 哈罗德·克里克
My name's on the goddamn buzzer! HaroId Crick.
麦卡锡大街1893号 2B座
Apartment 2-B, 1 893 McCarthy!
- 你说的是1893号? - 是的!
-Did you say 1 893? -Yes!
我不太肯定这就是情节
I'm not exactIy sure it was pIot.
我希望你说这只是个倒霉的巧合
I was hoping you'd say it was just a reaIIy bad coincidence.
你保单过期那天遇到个保险代理人是巧合
Meeting an insurance agent the day your poIicy runs out is coincidence.
接到国王的信说他要来拜访那是情节
Getting a Ietter from the emperor saying that he's visiting is pIot.
公寓被起重机拆了…
Having your apartment eaten by a wrecking baII...
完全是另一回事
...is something eIse entireIy.
哈罗德 你没有掌握自己的命运
HaroId, you don't controI your fate.
- 我知道 - 是吗?
-I know. -You do?
好吧 跟我来
Okay. Come with me.
嘿 汤姆 能把这个留到明天吗?
Hey, Tom, can you Ieave that tiII tomorrow?
你是对的 这个叙述者很可能要杀死你…
You were right. This narrator might very weII kiII you...
所以我建议你把这些都忘了 过你的日子去吧
...so I humbIy suggest that you just forget aII this and go Iive your Iife.
我就在过我的日子 我很想接着过我的日子
I am Iiving my Iife. I'd Iike to continue to Iive my Iife.
我知道 当然 我是说所有这些事 不管你还剩下几天
I know. Of course. I mean aII of it. However Iong you have Ieft.
我是说 霍华德 用这些日子去冒险
You know, I mean, Howard, you couId use it to have an adventure.
比如发明点东西 或者仅仅是读完《罪与罚》
You know, invent something, or just finish reading Crime and Punishment.
见鬼 哈罗德 如果你想的话 你可以只吃煎饼
HeII, HaroId, you couId just eat nothing but pancakes if you wanted.
你怎么回事?
What's wrong with you?
嘿 我不想只吃煎饼 我想活着
Hey. I don't wanna eat nothing but pancakes. I wanna Iive.
谁会在煎饼和活着之间选择…
Who in their right mind in a choice between pancakes and Iiving...
煎饼?
...chooses pancakes?
哈罗德 如果你停下来想一想 我相信你能明白…
HaroId, if you'd pause to think I beIieve you'd reaIize...
答案不可避免地决定于
...that that answer's inextricabIy contingent...
你所过的生活的类型
...upon the type of Iife being Ied...
当然 还有你吃的煎饼的质量
...and, of course, the quaIity of the pancakes.
你不明白我的意思
You don't understand what I'm saying.
我明白
Yes, I do.
但是你要明白这不是哲学或是文学理论
But you have to understand that this isn't a phiIosophy or a Iiterary theory...
或者是我的故事 这是我的人生
...or a story to me. It's my Iife.
当然 那就去过你一直想要的生活吧
AbsoIuteIy. So just go make it the one you've aIways wanted.
我从没想过他们要吃…
I never expected that they wouId have--
- 1个还是2个? - 1个
-Do you want one, two? -I want one.
- 1个? - 2个
-One? -I want two.
好吧 这就是你的房间
AII right, so here's your room.
或者我喜欢称之为睡仓2号
Or as I Iike to caII it, SIeep Pod Two.
谢谢 戴维
Thanks, Dave.
别客气 伙计 很高兴你到这来
No probIem, dude. It'II be nice having you around.
- 你打算待多久? - 我也不知道
-How Iong you pIanning on staying? -I'm not sure.
戴维 我能问个抽象 完全是假设的问题吗?
Dave, can I pose a somewhat abstract, pureIy hypotheticaI question?
当然
Sure.
如果你知道你会死去…
If you knew you were gonna die...
很快就死去…
...possibIy soon...
你会做什么呢?
...what wouId you do?
我不知道
Wow, I don't know.
我是世界上最富有的人吗?
Am I the richest man in the worId?
不 你就是你
No, you're you.
我有超能力吗?
Do I have a superpower?
不 你就是你
No, you're you.
我知道我就是我 但我有超能力吗?
I know I'm me, but do I have a superpower?
不 你为什么会有超能力?
No, why wouId you have a superpower?
不知道 你说这是假设的
I don't know, you said it was hypotheticaI.
好吧 你有 你对数学很在行
Fine. Yes. You're reaIIy good at math.
那不算超能力 那是技巧
That's not a power, that's a skiII.
好吧 你对数学在行 而且你是隐形的
Okay, you're good at math and you're invisibIe.
- 你知道你会死去 - 好的 好的
-And you know you're gonna die. -Okay, okay.
很简单 我要去空间夏令营
That's easy, I'd go to space camp.
空间夏令营?
Space camp?
是的 是在阿拉巴马 在那里孩子们学怎样成为宇航员
Yeah, it's in AIabama. It's where kids go to Iearn how to become astronauts.
我9岁开始就一直想去
I've aIways wanted to go since I was 9.
你隐形而且要去空间夏令营?
You're invisibIe and you'd go to space camp?
我没提隐形 你提的
I didn't pick invisibIe, you picked invisibIe.
你去夏令营是不是岁数太大了?
Aren't you too oId to go to space camp?
永远不嫌老 伙计
You're never too oId to go to space camp, dude.
空间夏令营
Space camp.
122把吉他
One hundred and twenty-two guitars.
732根弦
Seven hundred and thirty-two strings.
257块治音器
Two hundred and fifty-seven pickups.
189把音量旋钮
One hundred and eighty-nine volume knobs.
哈罗德站在那 面对着他最古老的渴望
Here Harold stood, face to face with his oldest desire.
站着几乎是哈罗德唯一做的事情
And stand is almost all Harold did.
不只是找一把吉他
lt wasn't just about finding a guitar.
是找一把能对哈罗德说点什么的吉他
lt was about finding a guitar that said something about Harold.
很不幸 这把吉他说：
Unfortunately, this guitar said:
"当我回到佐治亚的时候 那个女人会感受到我的痛苦的"
''When l get back to Georgia, that woman gonna feel my pain. ''
这排里的这把说：
This one said something along the lines of:
"为什么 是的 这些裤头是合成纤维的"
''Why, yes, these pants are Lycra. ''
这几把说"我很敏感 很有同情心…
These said, ''l'm very sensitive, very caring...
我一点也不知道怎样弹吉他"
...and l have absolutely no idea how to play the guitar. ''
"我要补偿点什么 猜猜是什么"
''l'm compensating for something. Guess what. ''
然后哈罗德看到了这把
And then Harold saw it.
一把受过严重虐待而损坏的 海绿色泡沫芬达吉他…
A damaged and terribly mistreated sea-foam-green Fender...
望着他
...staring back at him.
尽管有明显的损坏
Despite its obvious maladies...
这把吉他语气里带着自信和自傲
...the guitar spoke with conviction and swagger.
实际上 它平静地望着哈罗德的眼睛 说
ln fact, it looked Harold directly in the eye and very plainly stated:
"我摇起来"
''l rock. ''
深呼吸 注意点!
Just breathe. Watch it!
我们这有一位21岁男性胸部受到枪伤
We've got a 2 1 -year-oId maIe with a gunshot wound to the chest.
没错
There you go.
群殴时中枪了? 哈罗德不是什么帮派的
Shot in a gang fight? HaroId's not in a gang.
那个穿粗花呢衣服的人?
Man in tweed?
他没什么毛病 他只是看着病人
There's nothing wrong with him, he just Iikes Iooking at sick peopIe.
不屑地说怪话
OddIy spoken with disdain.
这样不行
This isn't working.
我不知道我们为何到这来
WeII-- I don't even know why we're here.
我认为我们不该来这
I don't think we're supposed to be here.
- 你说我需要视觉刺激 - 我是说博物馆
-You said I needed visuaI stimuIi. -I meant a museum.
我不需要见鬼的博物馆 我需要衰弱的人
I don't need a goddamn museum. I need the infirm.
你就是
You are the infirm.
没错 问题是这些人没死
You're right. The probIem is these peopIe aren't dead...
他们只是受了重伤
...they're just severeIy injured.
抱歉 快死了的人在哪?
Excuse me, where are the dying peopIe?
这些人大多数是病了或受伤了…
Most of these peopIe are sick or injured--
这很好 别误会我
Which is great, don't get me wrong.
他们会好起来的 但这对我没用
--but they're gonna get better, which doesn't reaIIy heIp me.
有什么办法去看看再也好不起来的人吗?
Is there any way to see the peopIe who aren't going to get better?
什么?
Excuse me?
我想去看看 如果可能的话 那些挺不过去的人
I'd Iike to see, if at aII possibIe, the ones who aren't gonna make it.
就是那些肯定快死了的人
You know, the dead-for-sure ones.
对不起 你是不是受了什么刺激?
I'm sorry, are you suffering from anything?
仅仅是写作障碍
Just writer's bIock.
通过每次笨拙的弹奏
With every awkward strum...
哈罗德·克里克越来越坚信自我…
...Harold Crick became stronger in who he was...
树立自己的目标 明确活着的意义
...what he wanted, and why he was alive.
哈罗德不再独自吃饭
Harold no longer ate alone.
不再数笔画
He no longer counted brushstrokes.
- 哈罗德 回见 - 他不再打领带
-HaroId, I'II see you. -He no longer wore neckties.
再见 戴维
Bye, Dave.
而且不再担心打领带花费的时间
And, therefore, no longer worried about the time it took to put them on.
他不再数到汽车站的步数
He no longer counted his steps to the bus stop.
相反 哈罗德做起了以前让他害怕的事
lnstead, Harold did that which had terrified him before.
那些他多年来的周一到周五
That which had eluded him Monday through Friday...
都不曾想到的事
...for so many years.
正像很多朋克歌手的冰冷歌词
That which the unrelenting lyrics...
告诉他的那样
...of numerous punk-rock songs told him to do:
哈罗德·克里克享受了他的生活
Harold Crick lived his life.
但是尽管生活复苏…
But despite resuscitating his life...
希望重燃 脑筋变活…
...reviving his hope, and instilling a few wicked calluses...
哈罗德的旅途仍未完整
...Harold's journey was still incomplete.
哈罗德的手表不想让他错过又一个机会
And Harold's wristwatch wasn't about to let him miss another opportunity.
帕斯卡女士?
Ms. PascaI?
- 帕斯卡女士? - 克里克先生
-Ms. PascaI? -Mr. Crick.
- 嗨 - 嗨
-Hi. -Hi.
很高兴遇到你了
I'm gIad I caught you.
是吗?为什么?
Oh, yeah? Why?
因为我要把这个带给你
Because I wanted to bring these to you.
- 真的? - 是的
-ReaIIy? -Yeah.
那么你不能接受礼物 却能馈赠礼物?
So you can't accept gifts, but you can give them?
- 听着… - 我不知道
-Listen-- -I don't know.
这看上去有点不一致 是吧 克里克先生?
That seems a IittIe inconsistent, doesn't it, Mr. Crick?
非常不一致 是的
Very inconsistent, yes.
这么说吧 我要把它们买下
I'II teII you what. I'II purchase them.
- 不 - 不 不 不 真的…
-No. -No, no, no, reaIIy...
我要买下它们 这是什么?
...I'd Iike to purchase them. What are they?
这是面粉
FIours.
- 什么? - 我给你带来了面粉
-What? -I brought you fIours.
你就这么大老远端来的?
And you carried them aII the way here?
帕斯卡女士 我过去很古怪 我知道我古怪
Ms. PascaI, I've been odd and I know that I've been odd.
我需要你
And I want you.
- 什么? - 有很多理由
-What? -There's so many reasons.
我生活中有很多变化 经常是很咬文嚼字地…
There's so many infIuences in my Iife that are teIIing me...
它们告诉我…
...at times quite IiteraIIy...
我应该来把这个给你
...that I shouId come here and bring you these...
但我这么做是因为我需要你
...but I'm doing this because I want you.
你需要我?
You want me?
非常明确
In no uncertain terms.
不是有非常明确的
Isn't there some very cIear and estabIished...
关于友好往来的规定吗?
...ruIe about fraternization?
- 审计员—被审计者关系? - 是的
-Auditor-auditee protocoI? -Yeah.
是有 但我不在乎
Yeah, but I don't care.
- 为什么? - 因为我需要你
-Why? -Because I want you.
嗯…
WeII...
你不介意再多拿一段路吧?
...do you mind carrying those a IittIe bit further?
没问题
Okay.
好
你都记录下来了?
Did you make a key?
不 我只记在脑子里
No, I just committed it to memory.
- 蓝色的是大麦粉 - 这个呢?
-The bIue, that's barIey fIour. -What's that one?
- 橙色的? - 对
-The orange? -Yeah.
我忘了
I forget.
到了
Right here.
你要进来吗?
Do you wanna come up?
- 到你家? - 是的
-To your pIace? -Yeah.
我想可以吧
I guess I couId.
这不是面粉什么的主意吧?
Wasn't that the idea with the fIours and everything?
老实说 我只能想到"我需要你"
HonestIy, I onIy figured it out up to ''I want you.''
听着 克里克先生…
Listen, Mr. Crick...
我想我喜欢你
...I think I Iike you.
但是在我做什么鲁莽的事情之前 我想确认一下
And before I do anything rash, I'd Iike to make sure.
我希望你进来
I'd Iike you to come up.
很荣幸
I'd be honored.
很好
Great.
对 他是疯子
Yeah, he was nuts though.
他想确认合同时被抓住了
He got caught when he tried to get the contract notarized.
不会吧
No. No.
好吃吗?
Was it good?
谢谢
Thank you.
- 别客气 - 我来帮你吧
-You're weIcome. -Can I heIp you?
不用了 我把它们泡在水池里 你坐到沙发上吧
No, no, I'm gonna put them in the sink. Go sit down on the couch.
你会弹吉他?
So do you pIay the guitar?
- 什么? - 你会弹吉他?
-What? -Do you pIay the guitar?
很糟糕 有人拿它向我换的结婚蛋糕
TerribIy. Someone traded me that for a wedding cake.
是不是我要为这个去报税了?
Does that mean I have to cIaim it on my taxes now?
- 不 我已经把总结报告交了 - 哦 谢谢
-No. I'II Ieave it out of my finaI report. -Oh, thanks.
你会弹吗?
Do you pIay?
不算吧 我只会一支歌
Not reaIIy. I onIy know one song.
哦 弹弹吧
Oh, pIay it.
实际上 我还不怎么熟
No, I don't know it that weII, actuaIIy.
弹吧 我保证不会笑的
No, come on. I promise I'm not gonna Iaugh at you. PIay it.
不了 也许以后吧
No, no, no. Maybe some other time.
好吧
AII right.
帕斯卡女士?
Ms. PascaI?
- 我… - 我明白
-I.... -I know.
我也需要你
I want you too.
哈罗德的生活充满了重要而平凡的时刻
Harold's life was filled with moments both significant and mundane.
但是对哈罗德来说 这些时刻完全是没法区分…
But to Harold, those moments remained entirely indistinguishable...
除了这个
...except for this.
当安娜轻叹一声有恢复常态时
As Ana let out a soft sigh and repositioned herself against him...
哈罗德从心底知道…
...Harold knew somewhere in his heart...
这是重要的一刻
...that this was one of the significant moments.
他知道她爱上他了
He knew she was falling in love with him.
希尔伯特教授 这是喜剧
Professor HiIbert. It's a comedy.
- 什么? - 喜剧
-What? -A comedy.
那个女人 原来恨我的那个 安娜·帕斯卡
The woman. The one who hates me. Ana PascaI?
- 昨夜… - 嗯
-Last night.... -Yeah?
她爱上我了
She's faIIing in Iove with me.
- 是吗? - 就像是个奇迹
-She is? -It's Iike a miracIe.
但夜里那个声音确认了
The voice confirmed it in the middIe of the night.
这真棒 哈罗德先生
WeII, that's wonderfuI, HaroId.
我是说 这完全让我的名单无效了 但是很奇妙
I mean, it compIeteIy nuIIifies my Iist, but that's fantastic.
什么名单?
What Iist?
根据之前你我确定的标准
These are seven Iiving authors whose prior work...
有七位在世的作家
...wouId seem to make them candidates to write your story...
他们先前的作品描写的是可能你
...based on the criteria you and I previousIy determined.
如果你这位叙述者还活着 她就在这名单上
If your narrator is aIive, she's on this Iist.
但是既然你要快乐地生活下去
But it appears the Iist is of IittIe use to you now.
看上去这名单对你没什么用了
Now that you're gonna Iive happiIy ever after.
哦 天啊 这个女人 凯伦·艾芙 她是我最喜欢的作者之一
Oh, goodie. This woman, Karen EiffeI, she's one of my favorite authors.
- 嗨 - 嗨
-Hi. -Hi.
美好的悲剧 很美 总之…
BeautifuI tragedies. Just beautifuI. Anyway...
我把这名单给你抄一份 以防万一
...Iet me quickIy copy this Iist for you, just in case.
反社会作家
Sociopathic author.
- 我只想谢谢你 - 当然
-I just wanted to thank you. -Of course.
听着 你要是再听到那个叙述者的声音 一定要告诉我
Listen, pIease, you must teII me if you hear the voice of the narrator again...
只作我自己启发之用
...just for my own edification.
我会的
I wiII.
嗯 叫做《死亡和税收》
Well, it's called Death and Taxes.
我 你知道 我就是德克萨斯人
Wow. You know, l'm from Texas.
不 不是"德克萨斯" 是"税收" （英文中两个词很接近）
No. Not ''Texas. '' Taxes.
《死亡和税收》 《死亡和税收》
Death and Taxes. Death and Taxes.
- 税收 - 就像本杰明·富兰克林引用的那样
Taxes. Like the Benjamin Franklin quote.
很准确
Precisely so.
这女士真能包装 告诉你们
This lady's a package, l'm telling you.
告诉大家 下本书是说什么的?
Tell us, what is this next book going to be about?
说的是互相联系
lt's about interconnectivity.
死亡隐约的确定
The looming certainty of death.
人们风格的附属
Men's fashion accessories.
- 哦 天啊 是她 - 什么?
-Oh, my God, that's her. -What?
- 就是这个声音 她就是叙述者 - 不 不可能是她
-That's the voice. She's the narrator. -No, that can't be right.
我很确定
No, I'm positive.
哈罗德 这是十年前的采访
HaroId, this interview's a decade oId.
我看男人们不再穿带袖口链扣的衬衫了
l didn't think anyone actually wore cuff links anymore.
就是她
That's her.
- 她是英国人? - 就是她
-She's British? -She's her.
- 凯伦·艾芙? - 希尔伯特教授 我认识那个声音
-Karen EiffeI? -Professor HiIbert, I know that voice.
糟糕
Crap.
- 怎么了? - 首先 她不在名单上
-What's wrong? -First of aII, she wasn't on my Iist.
我以为你会提到她的口音…
I figured you wouId have mentioned the accent and she doesn't....
她杀人
She kiIIs peopIe.
- 什么? - 每本书里她都…
-What? -In every book she--
那些书都是关于… 他们死了 她杀死了他们
The books are aII about-- They die. She kiIIs them.
- 杀死谁? - 主人公
-KiIIs who? -The heroes.
《四张黑面纱》 说什么的?
Four BIack VeiIs. What is that?
说的是有个女孩很快相继…
lt's about a girl who loses several members of her family...
失去了家里好几个成员
...in quick succession.
她在哪?
Where is she?
追踪不到的 相信我 我曾上过一节关于她的课
She's untraceabIe. BeIieve me, I used to teach a cIass on her.
我给她写过信 我是说 她是个隐士
I've written her Ietters. I mean, she's a hermit, she's a recIuse.
这就是她上一本书
Here. Here's the Iast book she wrote.
看看版权页 她10年来什么都没出版
Look at the copyright. She hasn't pubIished anything in 1 0 years.
她对这城市有所了解 她住在这里吗?
She had knowIedge of the city. Does she Iive here?
以前住在这 是的 但是…
She used to, yes, but I mean--
班内克出版公司 华莱士大街2267号 这就是她的出版商?
Banneker Press. 2267 WaIIace Street. Is that her pubIisher?
你没在听 我是说你即使找到她 她也不会…
You're not Iistening. I said even if you find her she's not gonna--
谢谢你的帮助
Thank you for your heIp.
她只写悲剧!
She onIy writes tragedies!
我不信上帝
l don't believe in God.
好的 他给她带来了面粉
Okay, he's bringing her fIours.
凯 你到哪去了?
Kay, where you been?
我去买香烟…
I went out to buy cigarettes...
我想出来怎样杀死哈罗德·克里克了
...and I figured out how to kiII HaroId Crick.
买烟?
Buying cigarettes?
正当我…走出商店
As I was-- When I came out of the store...
就眼前一亮
...it came to me.
如何呢?
How?
彭妮 就像任何值得写的东西…
WeII, Penny, Iike anything worth writing...
这是可遇而不可求的
...it came inexpIicabIy and without method.
我明白 发生了什么事?
I see. Then what happens?
很完美 实际上 我不敢相信我以前怎么没想到
It's perfect, actuaIIy. I can't beIieve I didn't think of it earIier.
很简单 讽刺…
It's simpIe, ironic...
可能让人心碎
...possibIy heartbreaking.
就是这个?
Is that it?
是的
Yes.
- 你写在了传单上? - 在公车上写的
-You wrote it on IegaI sheets? -On the bus.
不错嘛
WeII, then.
我今天就能写完
So I'II finish it today.
我会通知出版商的
I'II Iet the pubIishers know.
我去收拾行李
I'II begin packing my things.
我很感谢
I appreciate it.
- 嗨 你好 嗨 - 有什么需要效劳的吗?
-Hi. HeIIo. Hi. -May I heIp you?
我要和凯伦·艾芙通话
I need to speak to Karen EiffeI.
- 什么? - 凯伦·艾芙
-I'm sorry? -Karen EiffeI.
她是你们作者之一 我要和她谈谈
She's one of your authors. I need to taIk to her.
先生 她不在这里
WeII, sir, she's not here.
我知道 我要找到她 我要知道她在哪
No. No, I know. I need to find her. I need to know where she is.
我们只是出版商
We're just the pubIishers.
当然 但一定有办法我能联系到她
Right. Of course. But there must be a way that I can contact her.
我们只有读者来信上的地址
We have the address where her fan maiI is sent.
我不能发信 这很紧急
No, I can't send maiI. It's urgent.
你怎么知道她的?
How do you know her?
- 我是她弟弟 - 她弟弟?
-I'm her brother. -Her brother?
- 小舅子 - 她有妹妹吗?
-Her brother-in-Iaw. -She has a sister?
不 我嫁给了她弟弟
No, I'm married to her brother.
不是在这个州 是在别的州
Not in this state, the one over.
先生 我要请你离开
Sir, I'm gonna have to ask you to Ieave.
不 好吧 听着
No. Okay. Listen.
我是她的一个角色 我是新角色 新书里面的
I'm one of her characters. I'm new. I'm in her new book.
她要杀死我 不是实际的 是在书里
And she's going to kiII me. Not actuaIIy. But in the book.
但我认为那样实际会杀死我的 所以我要和她谈谈
But I think it'II actuaIIy kiII me so I just need to taIk to her...
让她住手
...and ask her to stop.
嗨 哈罗德 毛衣不错
Hi, HaroId. Nice sweater.
嗨 哈罗德 电话坏了
Hi, HaroId. Phones are out.
嘿 哈罗德 4632的19%是的多少?
Hey, HaroId, 1 9 percent of 4632...?
嘿 哈罗德 休假回来了?
Hey, HaroId. Back from your vaca?
嘿 哈罗德 看上去很不错
Hey. Looking good.
- 他看上去很糟糕 - 嗯 受刺激了
-He Iooks terribIe. -Yeah, banged up.
不管他去哪 我都不想去
Wherever he went, I do not want to go.
告我不在那吧
Book me not there.
他完全无视我
He's totaIIy ignoring me.
嘿 看 他来了
Here, Iook at this now. There he goes.
见到你很高兴
It was good having you.
- 哦 伙计 电话坏了 - 能用一下你的手机吗?
-Oh, dude, the phones are out. -Can I borrow your ceII phone?
- 没信号 - 见鬼
-The signaI's down. -Damn it.
- 你没事吧? - 戴维 我需要帮助
-You aII right? -Dave, I need a favor.
- 当然 什么事? - 给我点零钱好吗?
-Sure, what is it? -Can I have some change?
片刻间 哈罗德就跑过广场
Within moments, Harold found himself running across the plaza...
直奔最近的付费电话亭
...heading for the nearest pay phone.
终于 他发现了一部
At last, he spotted it.
但当哈罗德走近时 他发现被占用了
But as Harold neared the phone, he saw it was occupied...
那是一个80多岁的老头 准备去接在丹佛的女儿
...by an octogenarian determined to reach his daughter in Denver...
不管要用多长时间
...no matter how many quarters it took.
很幸运 哈罗德想起
Fortunately, Harold remembered a bank of phones...
在第六大街地铁隧道有几部电话
...in the Sixth Street subway tunnel.
孩子不是爱普斯坦夫人 我女儿叫爱普斯坦夫人
The baby's name isn't Mrs. Epstein. My daughter's name is Mrs. Epstein.
第一部电话不出拨号音
The first phone failed to give a dial tone.
第二部似乎是
And the second seemed to be splattered...
被喷了一层胶水
...with a fresh batch of mucus.
哈罗德拿起了第三部电话…
Harold dialed the third phone...
每次按在数字键上都重重有力
...fervently making sure to give each number key a specific forceful push.
[电话铃响了]
[电话铃又响了]
别接!
Don't answer that!
你不是说电话从来不…
Didn't you say this phone never r--?
[电话铃响了第三次]
- 喂? - 是凯伦·艾芙吗?
-HeIIo? -Is this Karen EiffeI?
- 是的 - 我叫哈罗德·克里克
-Yes. -My name is HaroId Crick.
我相信你在写一部我的故事
I beIieve you're writing a story about me.
- 什么? - 我叫哈罗德·克里克
-I'm sorry? -My name is HaroId Crick.
- 这是玩笑吗? - 不是
-Is this a joke? -No.
我在国税局上班 艾芙小姐 我叫哈罗德·克里克
No, I work for the IRS. My name, Miss EiffeI, is HaroId Crick.
当我工作中检查文件文件的时候 我听见深不可测 一望无际的大海声
When l go through the files at work l hear a deep and endless ocean.
- 哦 天…! - 艾芙小姐?
-Oh, G--! -Miss Eiffel?
喂?
HeIIo?
艾芙小姐?喂?
Miss Eiffel? Hello?
让他进来
Let him in.
你好
HeIIo.
我叫彭妮 我是凯的助理
I'm Penny. I'm Kay's assistant.
哦 我是哈罗德 她的主要角色
Oh, I'm HaroId. Her main character.
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
艾芙小姐?
Miss EiffeI?
你的头发 你的眼睛
Your hair. Your eyes.
你的手指
Your fingers.
你的鞋子
Your shoes.
你好
HeIIo.
我叫哈罗德·克里克
I'm HaroId Crick.
我知道
I know.
你是怎样找到我的?
How did you find me?
我们10多年前查过你的帐…
We audited you a IittIe more than 1 0 years ago...
档案中有你的号码
...and your number was in the fiIe.
抱歉 但这实在是太奇怪了
I'm sorry, but this is incredibIy strange.
你和我说吧
You're teIIing me.
你不觉得你疯了吗?
Didn't you think you were crazy?
有点吧
Sort of.
但你每件事都是对的 每件事
But then you were right about everything. Like, everything.
然后你说 "他毫不知晓"
And then you said, ''LittIe did he know.''
- "他毫不知晓?" - 是的 第三人称
-''LittIe did he know''? -Yeah. It's third-person omniscient.
天啊
Jesus.
意思是除了我之外还有人
Which meant it was, weII, you know, someone other than me.
最后希尔伯特教授就是这么说的
At Ieast that's what Professor HiIbert said.
希尔伯特教授?
Professor HiIbert?
- 朱尔斯·希尔伯特教授? - 是的
-Professor JuIes HiIbert? -Yeah.
他喜欢你的书
Yeah, he Ioves your books.
我喜欢他的来信 我不…
I Iove his Ietters. I don't--
那么你明白我为何必须要找到你
So you understand why I had to find you...
…要你别杀死我 - 什么?
-...and ask you not to kiII me. -What?
我是说 很明显 你还没写结尾
I mean, obviousIy you haven't written the end.
哈罗德…
HaroId....
既然我们见过面 你看到我确实存在…
I mean, now since we've met and you can see that I exist...
你就不会杀死我了 对吧?
...you're not gonna kiII me, right?
你写了吗?
Have you written it?
我能…不
I can-- No.
- 你写出来了? - 只有提纲
-Have you written it? -An outIine.
好吧 但只是个提纲 对吧?
Okay. But it's just an outIine, right?
- 算是吧 - "算是"?
-Yeah, sort of. -''Sort of''?
- 还没打出来? - "没打出来"?
-It's just not typed. -''Not typed''?!
- 也许没问题 - 什么意思?
-Maybe that's okay. -What does that mean?
- 抱歉 我在尽力去写一本书 - "没问题"是什么意思?
-I'm sorry, I'm trying to write a book. -What do you mean it's ''okay''?
- 你抱歉是什么意思? - 凯
-What do you mean you're sorry? -Kay.
让他读读吧
Let him read it.
让他读读
- 你找到她了? - 嗯
-Did you find her? -Yeah.
- 然后呢? - 我可能已经死了…
-And? -I may aIready be dead...
只是还没打出来
...just not typed.
就是这个?
Is that it?
你读了吗?
Did you read it?
我试过 但我做不到
I tried, but I couIdn't.
你要读一读
You have to read it.
你要该告诉我该做什么不该做什么
You have to teII me what to do or what not to do.
如果我能避免…
If I can avoid it....
如果我有机会…
If I have a chance....
求求你
PIease.
好吧
Okay.
好的
这是你的制服
And here's your uniform.
贝妮塔在外面 她会分配你储物柜
It's a go. Banetta's outside, she'II assign you your Iocker.
- 去吧 - 我准备好了
-And you roII. -I'm ready.
希尔伯特教授?
Professor HiIbert?
- 嗨 哈罗德 - 嗨
-Hi, HaroId. -Hi.
你看上去很累
You Iook tired.
不 不 只是冷静
No, no, just caIm.
哈罗德 我很遗憾
HaroId, I'm sorry.
你必须死去
You have to die.
什么?
What?
这是她的杰作
It's her masterpiece.
这可能是她璀璨的事业中最重要的一部小说
It's possibIy the most important noveI in her aIready stunning career...
除非你在结尾死去 这才是一部佳作
...and it's absoIuteIy no good unIess you die at the end.
我已经读了一遍又一遍…
I've been over it again and again...
我知道这对你有多难
...and I know how hard this is for you to hear.
你要我去有意地面对死亡?
You're asking me to knowingIy face my death?
是的
Yes.
真的?
ReaIIy?
是的
Yes.
我想…我想你会找到什么…
I thought you'd.... I thought you'd find something.
很抱歉 哈罗德
I'm sorry, HaroId.
我们能不能试试看她能否改一下?
Can't we just try and just see if she can change it?
- 不行 - 不行?
-No. -No?
哈罗德…
HaroId...
大环境下这是无关紧要的
...in the grand scheme it wouIdn't matter.
- 这很重要 - 不是
-Yes, it wouId. -No.
我可以改变
I couId change.
我可以辞职
I couId quit my job.
我可以和安娜远走高飞
I couId go away with Ana.
我可以重新做人
I couId be someone eIse.
哈罗德 听我说
HaroId, Iisten to me.
我现在不想死
I can't die right now.
这真不是好时候
It's just reaIIy bad timing.
没人想死 哈罗德 但是很不幸我们没办法
No one wants to die, HaroId, but unfortunateIy we do.
哈罗德…
HaroId....
哈罗德 听我说
HaroId, Iisten to me.
哈罗德 你某一天会死去
HaroId, you wiII die someday, sometime.
在银行心力衰竭
Heart faiIure at the bank.
吃薄荷糖时憋死
Choke on a mint.
度假时染上慢性病
Some Iong, drawn-out disease you contracted on vacation.
你会死的 肯定会的
You wiII die. You wiII absoIuteIy die.
躲得过初一也躲不过十五
Even if you avoid this death, another wiII find you.
而且我保证远非她写得那样…
And I guarantee that it won't be nearIy as poetic or meaningfuI...
富有诗意和意味深长
...as what she's written.
我很抱歉…
I'm sorry...
但这是所有悲剧的本性 哈罗德
...but it's the nature of aII tragedies, HaroId.
主人公死去 但故事永流传
The hero dies, but the story Iives on forever.
- 那边有空座 - 不 我就要坐在这
-There's an empty seat right there. -No, I wanna sit down over here.
凯?
Kay?
你觉得我杀死了多少人?
How many peopIe do you think I've kiIIed?
- 凯 - 多少?
-Kay. -How many?
- 我不知道 - 8个
-I don't know. -Eight.
- 凯… - 我杀死了8个人 我数过
-Kay-- -I've kiIIed eight peopIe. I counted.
他们都是虚构的 起来吧
They're fictionaI. Get up.
哈罗德·克里克可不是虚构的
HaroId Crick isn't fictionaI.
- 我不… - 他不是虚构的 彭妮
-I don't-- -He isn't fictionaI, Penny.
我写的每本书都是以某人死去结尾 每本书都是
Every book I've ever written ends with someone dying. Every one.
很多还是真正的好人
ReaIIy nice peopIe too.
那本写海伦 那个教师的就是
The book about HeIen the schooIteacher.
我在暑假前一天杀死了她
I kiIIed her the day before summer vacation.
多残忍啊
How crueI is that?
那个很坏的工程师 爱德华
And the civiI engineer, Edward.
我把他…
The one I trapped...
在上下班高峰用心脏病困了1小时
...with a heart attack in rush hour.
我杀死了他
I kiIIed him.
我杀死了…
I kiIIed....
彭妮 我把他们都杀死了
Penny, I kiIIed them aII.
艾芙小姐 艾芙小姐
Miss EiffeI? Miss EiffeI?
- 哈罗德 - 嗨
-HaroId. -Hi.
- 我刚看完 - 你真是…
-I just finished it. -You just....
我在公车上一口气看完了
Yeah, I read it aII in one read on the bus.
很感人
It's IoveIy.
我喜欢吉他那部分
I Iike the part about the guitars.
谢谢 谢谢… 听着 我…
WeII, thanks, thanks. Goo-- WeII, Iisten, I'm--
我读过了 很喜欢 结局只能有一种
No, I read it and I Ioved it. And there's onIy one way it can end.
我是说 我在文学方面没多少背景知识
I mean, I don't have much background in Iiterary anything...
但是这个很显而易见
...but this seems simpIe enough.
我喜欢你的书 我想你应该把它写完
I Iove your book. And I think you shouId finish it.
他死前那一夜
The night before his death...
哈罗德出人意料地处理了一些平常事务
...Harold unsuspectingly went about some usual business.
他出色地完成了审计项目
He finished his outstanding audits.
打了几通延误了的电话
He made a few phone calls he had been putting off.
听着 你的节目有年龄限制吗?
Listen, does your program have an age Iimit?
然后他到帕斯卡女士的家
And he traveled to Ms. Pascal's...
她给他做了肉馅糕和巧克力布丁
...where she made him meat loaf and chocolate pudding...
他们两个看了老电影
...and the two watched old movies.
那是个很愉快的夜晚
lt was a nice enough evening.
在其他场合下这个夜晚会很普通
And in any other circumstance it would've seemed commonplace.
实际上 唯一让那个夜晚不平凡的…
ln fact, the only thing that made this night significant...
就是接下来的那个早晨
...was the morning it preceded.
我要告诉你一件事
I have to teII you something.
是吗?
You do?
是的
I do.
- 是秘密吗? - 算是吧
-Is it a secret? -Sort of.
说吧
TeII me.
我爱你
I adore you.
我也爱你
I adore you too.
- 就这个? - 不是
-That it? -No.
我必须要告诉你
I have to teII you this.
我只要你仔细听
I just want you to Iisten carefuIIy.
好吧
Okay.
你可以从你卖出的食品中
You can deduct the vaIue of aII the food you give away...
…扣除一部分算作慈善捐助 - 哈罗德
-...as a charitabIe contribution. -HaroId.
不 不 不 实际上那总数比你现在拒交的税还多
No, no, no. In fact it amounts to more than what you're currentIy withhoIding.
而且不违反任何税法
And it doesn't break any tax Iaws.
哈罗德 那意图就是违反税法
HaroId, the point is to break the tax Iaws.
我也想让这世界变得更美好 安娜
I wanna make the worId a better pIace too, Ana.
我想这个办法能让你免受牢狱之灾
I think that means keeping you out of jaiI.
好吧
Okay.
明白
Okay?
- 嗯 - 好
-Yeah. -Okay.
如果你到这来
If you come over here...
在我耳边多谈谈税务的事情…
...and taIk a IittIe more tax taIk in my ear.
因为我非常喜欢
Because I Iike it so much.
过去两周以来哈罗德改变了很多：
Much had changed for Harold over the past few weeks:
他走路的姿势
His attitude towards work.
数数的习惯
His habitual counting.
他的爱情生活
His love life.
但是所有这些进行的变化中最重要的
But of all the transmutations Harold Crick had undergone...
也许就是今天在他上班路上…
...perhaps the most significant was that today on his return to work...
他没错过8点17分的克罗内克公车
...he was not late for the 8: 1 7 Kronecker bus.
哈罗德不知道的是
What Harold had not understood...
四周前的那个星期三…
...about that Wednesday four weeks prior...
他从路人那问来的时间…
...was that the time he received from his fellow commuter...
实际上 比实际时间晚了3分钟
...was, in fact, three full minutes later than the actual time...
因此 这时间比他先前生活中 和手表上设定的时间
...and, therefore, three full minutes later...
晚了3分钟
...than the time to which his watch and life had been previously set.
这不是最严重的错误
Not the worst of errors.
但是如果哈罗德不把他的手表 设定到错误时间
But if Harold had not set his watch to the incorrect time...
哈罗德会又一次刚好赶上8点17分 克罗内克公车
...Harold would have again barely caught the 8: 1 7 Kronecker bus.
并且他就不会在这个特别地星期五…
And he would not be approaching the bus stop...
准时在8点14分到达公车站
...precisely at 8: 1 4 this particular Friday.
对不起
Excuse me.
哈罗德?
HaroId?
另一个容易被忽略的事实…
An otherwise ignorable fact...
直到意想不到的事情发生了
...until the unthinkable occurred.
哦 天啊 哦 天啊
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
大家待在座位上
I need for everyone to just stay seated.
别这样 孩子
Come on, son.
[哈罗德死…] ["死"字没打完]
- 怎么回事?我没看到他 - 不是你的错
-What happened? I didn't see him. -It was not your fauIt.
他正尽量救那孩子 打电话找你的主管
He was trying to heIp the boy. Get your supervisor.
真不敢相信
I don't beIieve this.
- 都是我的错 - 不是的
-It was aII my fauIt, though. -No, it wasn't.
他没事吧?
Is he okay?
- 看上去他还有呼吸 - 我觉得他没呼吸了
-It Iooks Iikes he's breathing. -I don't think he's breathing.
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
进来
Come in.
对不起
Excuse me.
您是希尔伯特教授吗?
Are you Professor HiIbert?
是的
Yes.
嗨 我是凯伦·艾芙
Hi. I'm Karen EiffeI.
我想我们有个共同的熟人
I beIieve we have a mutuaI acquaintance.
请坐
PIease, sit down.
不 我只是顺路来…
No, I just came by to....
给
Here.
- 就这些? - 是的
-Is that it? -Yes.
你读了吗?
Have you read it?
没什么问题吧?
Is that aII right?
是的
Yes.
我想 也许你对这个新结局感兴趣
I think, perhaps, you may be interested in the new ending.
下午好
Good afternoon.
嗨
Oh, hi.
你做了件勇敢的事情
It's a pretty brave thing you did.
冲到公车前非常勇敢
Stepping in front of that bus was pretty brave.
有点傻 但很勇敢
Kind of stupid, but pretty brave.
嗯
Oh, yeah.
那孩子没事吧
Is that boy okay?
他没事 只是划破点皮
He's just fine. Scratched up is aII.
不错
Oh, good.
我还行吗?
Am I okay?
你没死
WeII, you're not dead.
另一方面 看上去你撞伤头部
On the other hand, it Iooks Iike you cracked your head...
腿脚三处骨折
...you broke three bones in your Ieg and foot...
四根肋骨骨折 左臂骨折
...you suffered four broken ribs, fractured your Ieft arm...
右动脉破裂 这本该置你于死地的
...and severed an artery in your right, which shouId've kiIIed you in minutes.
但令人吃惊的是…
But amazingIy...
你手表上一小块碎片堵住了动脉
...a shard of metaI from your watch obstructed the artery...
让出血量大为减少 救活了你的命
...keeping the bIood Ioss Iow enough to keep you aIive...
真够酷
...which is pretty cooI.
根据这些诊断
Yeah. So with some physicaI therapy...
休息几个月后 你就没事了
...a few months of rest, you shouId be fine.
算是吧 我们没法取出那片手表碎片
WeII, sort of. We weren't abIe to remove the shard of watch...
否则要冒动脉破裂的危险
...from your arm without risking severe arteriaI damage.
你会好起来的 你的余生里
You'II be okay. You'II just have a piece of watch...
胳膊中都会嵌着一片手表碎片
...embedded in your arm the rest of your Iife.
你很命大 克里克先生
You're very Iucky to be aIive, Mr. Crick.
嗯
Yeah.
- 莫卡特大夫 克里克先生有一位探望者 - 好
-Dr. Mercator, Mr. Crick has a visitor. -Sure.
- 天啊 哈罗德 - 嘿
-My God, HaroId. -Hey.
- 我没事 - 哈罗德
-I'm okay. It's aII right. -HaroId.
我没事
I'm fine.
哈罗德 不是的
HaroId, you're not fine.
看看你 伤得这么严重
Look at you. You're severeIy injured.
- 不 我没事 - 发生…发生了什么事?
-No, I'm fine. -What--? What happened?
我冲到了公车前
I stepped in front of a bus.
什么?为什么?
What? Why?
那有个孩子 我要把他推到路边
There was a boy. I had to push him out of the way.
什么?
What?
我不能让那孩子被撞到
I had to keep this boy from getting hit.
你冲到公车前去救一个孩子?
You stepped in front of a bus to save a IittIe boy?
我别无选择
I didn't have a choice.
我必须这样做
I had to.
这个…还好
It's.... It's okay.
- 不怎么好 - 不
-It's not great. -No.
还好 不赖
It's okay. It's not bad.
这不是这几年英文文学里最出色的一部
It's not the most amazing piece of EngIish Iiterature in severaI years...
但是…还好
...but it's okay.
你知道…
You know...
我想我还能接受"还好"
...I think I'm fine with ''okay.''
书剩下的部分就没什么意义了
It doesn't make sense with the rest of the book though.
不 我会重写剩下的
No, not yet. I'II rewrite the rest.
我的助理说 她会回到出版商那…
My assistant said she'd go back to the pubIisher...
…再争取一些时间 - 为什么?
-...and request more time. -Why?
不知道 但是很贴心
Don't know. It's awfuIIy sweet though.
不 你为何要重写这本书?
No, why did you change the book?
很多理由
Lots of reasons.
我意识到我不能那样做
I reaIized I just couIdn't do it.
因为他是真实的?
Because he's reaI?
因为那是关于一个人…
Because it's a book about a man...
他不知道他会死去 然后死掉了
...who doesn't know he's about to die and then dies.
但如果这个人知道他会死去 知道如何避免
But if the man does know he's going to die and dies anyway...
还是坦然死去…
...dies wiIIingIy, knowing he couId stop it, then....
我是说 这不是你要让他活下来那种人吗?
I mean, isn't that the type of man you want to keep aIive?
哈罗德咬了一口巴伐利亚糖曲奇…
As Harold took a bite of Bavarian sugar cookie...
他最终感到好像一切都会好起来
...he finally felt as if everything was going to be okay.
有时 当我们在恐惧 在绝望
Sometimes, when we lose ourselves in fear and despair...
在日常琐事 在一成不变
...in routine and constancy...
在无望 在悲剧面前迷失自我时
...in hopelessness and tragedy...
我们可以感谢上帝的巴伐利亚糖曲奇
...we can thank God for Bavarian sugar cookies.
很幸运 当没有曲奇的时候…
And fortunately, when there aren't any cookies...
我们仍能在我们身上那只熟悉的手上…
...we can still find reassurance in a familiar hand on our skin...
或是一种爱的手势上…
...or a kind and loving gesture...
或是细心的鼓励上…
...or a subtle encouragement...
或是一个爱的拥抱上
...or a loving embrace...
或是温暖的安慰上安下心来
...or an offer of comfort.
而忘掉医院的担架…
Not to mention hospital gurneys...
还有鼻帖…
...and nose plugs...
还有吃不饱的丹麦人…
...and uneaten Danish...
还有窃窃私语…
...and soft-spoken secrets...
还有芬达史崔特卡斯特吉他…
...and Fender Stratocasters...
也许还有偶尔一篇小说
...and maybe the occasional piece of fiction.
我们必须记住所有这一切…
And we must remember that all these things...
这些我们认为仅仅是平日生活中点缀的
...the nuances, the anomalies, the subtleties...
微妙 奇异 算计
...which we assume only accessorize our days...
它们的存在有着更伟大高尚的原因：
...are, in fact, here for a much larger and nobler cause:
它们是来救我们的命的
They are here to save our lives.
我知道这想法看上去很古怪
l know the idea seems strange.
但我也知道这恰好就是真实的
But l also know that it just so happens to be true.
这就是：
And so it was:
一只手表救了哈罗德·克里克
A wristwatch saved Harold Crick.